let questions = [

    {
        numb: 1,
        question: 'The size of basic datatypes can be changed according to 32 or 64-bit operating systems.',
        answer: 'B. False',
        options: [
            'A. True',
            'B. False'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 2,
        question: 'Which of the following is the correct format specifier for long double -types values in C++?',
        answer: 'C. %lf',
        options: [
            'A. %f',
            'B. %ld',
            'C. %lf',
            'D. %ldf'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 3,
        question: 'Does C++ language support both signed and unsigned literals?',
        answer: 'A. True',
        options: [
            'A. True',
            'B. False'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 4,
        question: 'Which of the following is not a basic type in C++?',
        answer: 'C. array',
        options: [
            'A. int',
            'B. float',
            'C. array',
            'D. char'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 5,
        question: 'For which type, is the format specifier "%i" used?',
        answer: 'A. int',
        options: [
            'A. int',
            'B. float',
            'C. array',
            'D. char'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 6,
        question: 'Which of the following is not a correct qualifier in C++?',
        answer: 'C. Sign qualifier',
        options: [
            'A. Size qualifier',
            'B. Type qualifier',
            'C. Sign qualifier',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 7,
        question: 'How many byte(s) does a short type take in C++?',
        answer: 'B. 2',
        options: [
            'A. 1',
            'B. 2',
            'C. 3',
            'D. 4'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 8,
        question: 'The operator + is',
        answer: 'C. Both Unary and Binary Operator',
        options: [
            'A. Unary Operator',
            'B. Binary Operator',
            'C. Both Unary and Binary Operator',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 9,
        question: 'The operator \'%\' is known as',
        answer: 'B. Modulus Operator',
        options: [
            'A. Division Operator',
            'B. Modulus Operator',
            'C. Percentage Operator',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 10,
        question: 'Which of the following operators is a ternary operator?',
        answer: 'D. ?:',
        options: [
            'A. +',
            'B. !=',
            'C. *',
            'D. ?:'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 11,
        question: 'Which of the following operators is known as the Scope Resolution Operator?',
        answer: 'A. ::',
        options: [
            'A. ::',
            'B. :',
            'C. .',
            'D. ->'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 12,
        question: 'Which of the following operators is known as the Referential Operator?',
        answer: 'C. .',
        options: [
            'A. ::',
            'B. :',
            'C. .',
            'D. sizeof'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 13,
        question: 'The sizeof() is a:',
        answer: 'A. Unary Operator',
        options: [
            'A. Unary Operator',
            'B. Binary Operator',
            'C. Ternary Operator',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 14,
        question: 'Which of the following operators is used to return the address of a variable?',
        answer: 'C. &',
        options: [
            'A. *',
            'B. ->',
            'C. &',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 15,
        question: 'Which of the following is known as the "value of" operator?',
        answer: 'A. *',
        options: [
            'A. *',
            'B. ->',
            'C. &',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 16,
        question: 'Which of the following is known as the "NOT" operator?',
        answer: 'B. !',
        options: [
            'A. ~',
            'B. !',
            'C. NOT(',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 17,
        question: 'Which of the following is not an arithmetic operator?',
        answer: 'B. !',
        options: [
            'A. %',
            'B. !',
            'C. +',
            'D. *'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 18,
        question: 'Which of the following statements is correct about global variables?',
        answer: 'B. A variable defined outside the function or block is known as a global variable.',
        options: [
            'A. A variable defined inside the function or block is known as a global variable.',
            'B. A variable defined outside the function or block is known as a global variable.',
            'C. Global variables can only declare inside the .h file.',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 19,
        question: 'Which of the following is the default storage class in C++?',
        answer: 'A. auto',
        options: [
            'A. auto',
            'B. extern',
            'C. register',
            'D. static'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 20,
        question: 'Which of the following is/are decision-making statements? 1- if statement 2- switch statement 3- conditional operators 4- none of the above',
        answer: 'D. 1, 2, and 3',
        options: [
            'A. 1 and 2',
            'B. 1 and 3',
            'C. Only 4',
            'D. 1, 2, and 3'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 21,
        question: 'Which of the following statements can replace the if-else statement?',
        answer: 'D. conditional operator',
        options: [
            'A. while loop',
            'B. do-while loop',
            'C. for loop',
            'D. conditional operator'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 22,
        question: 'Which of the following is an exit control loop?',
        answer: 'B. Do-while loop',
        options: [
            'A. While loop',
            'B. Do-while loop',
            'C. For loop',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 23,
        question: 'Which of the following loops is normally used for a menu-driven program?',
        answer: 'A. Do-while loop',
        options: [
            'A. Do-while loop',
            'B. For loop',
            'C. While loop',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 24,
        question: 'Which of the following loops is the best option when the number of iterations is known?',
        answer: 'B. For loop',
        options: [
            'A. While loop',
            'B. For loop',
            'C. Do-while loop',
            'D. All loops require that the iterations be known'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 25,
        question: 'Execution of a C++ program starts from',
        answer: 'C. main function',
        options: [
            'A. void function',
            'B. class',
            'C. main function',
            'D. user-defined function'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 26,
        question: 'Which of the following is a more effective way to call a function with arguments?',
        answer: 'B. Call by reference',
        options: [
            'A. Call by value',
            'B. Call by reference',
            'C. Call by address',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 27,
        question: 'How many minimum numbers of functions are required to execute a C++ program?',
        answer: 'B. 2',
        options: [
            'A. 1',
            'B. 2',
            'C. 3',
            'D. 4'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 28,
        question: 'What is the lifetime of a static variable declared in a user-defined function?',
        answer: 'C. Whole program',
        options: [
            'A. Within the function only',
            'B. Within the main function only',
            'C. Whole program',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 29,
        question: 'Which of the following statements is correct about inline functions?',
        answer: 'A. A function that is substituted at the place of call',
        options: [
            'A. A function that is substituted at the place of call',
            'B. A function that is called at compile time',
            'C. A function that contains only looping statements',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 30,
        question: 'Default values for a function are defined',
        answer: 'A. In function declaration',
        options: [
            'A. In function declaration',
            'B. In function definition',
            'C. During function call',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 31,
        question: 'Index of an array starts from',
        answer: 'C. 0',
        options: [
            'A. 1',
            'B. 2',
            'C. 0',
            'D. -1'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 32,
        question: 'In C++, the array name denotes',
        answer: 'A. The base address of the array',
        options: [
            'A. The base address of the array',
            'B. The first value of the array',
            'C. Last value of the array',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 33,
        question: 'If we create an array "Arr", which is the correct way to access the first element of the array?',
        answer: 'A. Arr[0]',
        options: [
            'A. Arr[0]',
            'B. 0[Arr]',
            'C. *(Arr+0)',
            'D. All of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 34,
        question: 'Can we create an array of objects in C++?',
        answer: 'A. Yes',
        options: [
            'A. Yes',
            'B. No'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 35,
        question: 'An array occupies memory space in',
        answer: 'A. Contiguous manner',
        options: [
            'A. Contiguous manner',
            'B. Fragmented manner',
            'C. Linked list',
            'D. None of these'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 36,
        question: 'How many dimensions are an array in C++?',
        answer: 'D. No limit',
        options: [
            'A. 1',
            'B. 2',
            'C. 3D',
            'D. No limit'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 37,
        question: 'Which of the following operators is known as the indirection operator?',
        answer: 'C. *',
        options: [
            'A. +',
            'B. &',
            'C. *',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 38,
        question: 'Which of the following is the incorrect way to declare a pointer?',
        answer: 'C. int & ptr',
        options: [
            'A. int ptr',
            'B. int *ptr',
            'C. int & ptr',
            'D. int ptr[]'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 39,
        question: 'A pointer can be initialized with',
        answer: 'D. All of the above',
        options: [
            'A. Address of variable of the same type',
            'B. NULL',
            'C. 0',
            'D. All of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 40,
        question: 'Which of the following is the correct way to get a value from pointer "ptr"?',
        answer: 'C. *ptr',
        options: [
            'A. ptr',
            'B. &ptr',
            'C. *ptr',
            'D. All of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 41,
        question: 'What is the size of a pointer?',
        answer: 'D. Vary from processor to processor',
        options: [
            'A. 4 bytes',
            'B. 8 bytes',
            'C. 16 bytes',
            'D. Vary from processor to processor'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 42,
        question: 'Which of the following can point to any type of variable?',
        answer: 'C. Void pointer',
        options: [
            'A. Far pointer',
            'B. Null pointer',
            'C. Void pointer',
            'D. Dangling pointer'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 43,
        question: 'Which type of memory is allocated using dynamic memory allocation?',
        answer: 'B. Heap',
        options: [
            'A. Stack',
            'B. Heap',
            'C. Static',
            'D. Program code'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 44,
        question: 'Which of the following is/are used for dynamic memory allocation? 1- malloc, 2- calloc, 3- new, 4- free',
        answer: 'D. All 1, 2, 3 and 4',
        options: [
            'A. 1 & 2',
            'B. 1, 2 & 4',
            'C. 2 & 3',
            'D. All 1, 2, 3 and 4'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 45,
        question: 'Can we allocate memory for an object dynamically?',
        answer: 'A. Yes',
        options: [
            'A. Yes',
            'B. No'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 46,
        question: 'Which of the following operators is used to release dynamically allocated memory space?',
        answer: 'D. delete',
        options: [
            'A. new',
            'B. release',
            'C. remove',
            'D. delete'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 47,
        question: '"delete" is an operator in C++',
        answer: 'A. Yes',
        options: [
            'A. Yes',
            'B. No'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 48,
        question: 'Which of the following is a valid way to allocate dynamic memory for an integer variable?',
        answer: 'D. All of the above',
        options: [
            'A. int *ptr = new int(111);',
            'B. int *ptr = NULL; ptr = new int;',
            'C. int *ptr = new int; *ptr = 111;',
            'D. All of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 49,
        question: 'Which of the following statements is correct about class in C++?',
        answer: 'C. Class is a blueprint for a data type that encapsulates data member and member functions.',
        options: [
            'A. Class is an instance that contains data member and member functions.',
            'B. Class is fundamental that contains data member and member functions.',
            'C. Class is a blueprint for a data type that encapsulates data member and member functions.',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 50,
        question: 'By default, members of a class are',
        answer: 'B. Private',
        options: [
            'A. Public',
            'B. Private',
            'C. Protected',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 51,
        question: 'What is the size of an empty class in C++?',
        answer: 'B. 0 byte',
        options: [
            'A. 1 byte',
            'B. 0 byte',
            'C. 2 byte',
            'D. 4 byte'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 52,
        question: 'Can we create multiple objects of a class in C++?',
        answer: 'A. Yes',
        options: [
            'A. Yes',
            'B. No'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 53,
        question: 'Which of the following operators is used to access the members using the object of a class?',
        answer: 'A. .',
        options: [
            'A. .',
            'B. ->',
            'C. *',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 54,
        question: 'Which of the following operators is used to access the members using the pointer to the object of a class?',
        answer: 'B. ->',
        options: [
            'A. .',
            'B. ->',
            'C. *',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 55,
        question: 'How many types of specifiers can be used in class in C++?',
        answer: 'C. 3',
        options: [
            'A. 1',
            'B. 2',
            'C. 3',
            'D. 4'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 56,
        question: 'Which of the following is a type of specifier that can be used in class in C++?',
        answer: 'D. All of the above',
        options: [
            'A. Public',
            'B. Private',
            'C. Protected',
            'D. All of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 57,
        question: 'How many types of specifiers can be used in class in C++?',
        answer: 'C. 3',
        options: [
            'A. 1',
            'B. 2',
            'C. 3',
            'D. 4'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 58,
        question: 'Which of the following statements is correct about constructors in C++?',
        answer: 'B. Constructor is used for initializing data members when an object gets created',
        options: [
            'A. A constructor is used to destroy an object.',
            'B. Constructor is used for initializing data members when an object gets created',
            'C. Constructor is used to call the private function from outside the class',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 59,
        question: 'How many parameters can be accepted by a default constructor?',
        answer: 'C. 0',
        options: [
            'A. 1',
            'B. 2',
            'C. 0',
            'D. Infinite'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 60,
        question: 'What is the return type of a constructor?',
        answer: 'D. None of these',
        options: [
            'A. void',
            'B. int',
            'C. float',
            'D. None of these'
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 61,
        "question": "If we did not create any constructor in the class, then which of the following constructors is automatically added to the class?",
        "answer": "B. Default constructor",
        "options": [
            "A. Copy constructor",
            "B. Default constructor",
            "C. Parameterized constructor",
            "D. None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 62,
        "question": "Constructor and Destructor have the same name but destructor is preceded by:",
        "answer": "A. ~",
        "options": [
            "A. ~",
            "B. @",
            "C. $",
            "D. #"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 63,
        "question": "Which of the following constructors is used to create an object by initializing data members using an existing object?",
        "answer": "C. Copy constructor",
        "options": [
            "A. Default constructor",
            "B. Dynamic constructor",
            "C. Copy constructor",
            "D. None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 64,
        "question": "When does a destructor gets called?",
        "answer": "B. When an object gets destroyed",
        "options": [
            "A. When an object gets created",
            "B. When an object gets destroyed",
            "C. After calling constructor",
            "D. None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 65,
        "question": "To overcome the ambiguity occurred due to multipath inheritance, C++ provides the keyword _____",
        "answer": "A. virtual",
        "options": [
            "A. virtual",
            "B. friend",
            "C. default",
            "D. None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 66,
        "question": "The procedure of creating a new class from one or more existing classes is termed as _____",
        "answer": "A. Inheritance",
        "options": [
            "A. Inheritance",
            "B. Polymorphism",
            "C. Encapsulation",
            "D. None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 67,
        question: 'Which of the following statements is correct about constructors in C++?',
        answer: 'B. Constructor is used to initializing data members when an object gets created',
        options: [
            'A. A constructor is used to destroy an object',
            'B. Constructor is used to initializing data members when an object gets created',
            'C. Constructor is used to call the private function from outside the class',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 68,
        question: 'How many parameters can be accepted by a default constructor?',
        answer: 'C. 0',
        options: [
            'A. 1',
            'B. 2',
            'C. 0',
            'D. Infinite'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 69,
        question: 'What is the return type of a constructor?',
        answer: 'D. None of the above',
        options: [
            'A. Void',
            'B. int',
            'C. Float',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 70,
        question: 'Which of the following is an incorrect type of constructor in C++?',
        answer: 'D. Friend constructor',
        options: [
            'A. Default constructor',
            'B. Parameterized constructor',
            'C. Copy constructor',
            'D. Friend constructor'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 71,
        question: 'If we did not create any constructor in the class, then which of the following constructors is automatically added to the class?',
        answer: 'B. Default constructor',
        options: [
            'A. Copy constructor',
            'B. Default constructor',
            'C. Parameterized constructor',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 72,
        question: 'Constructor and Destructor have the same name but destructor is preceded by:',
        answer: 'B. ~',
        options: [
            'A. ...',
            'B. ~',
            'C. Hybrid',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 73,
        question: 'Which of the following is the other name of compile-time polymorphism?',
        answer: 'A. Static polymorphism',
        options: [
            'A. Static polymorphism',
            'B. Executing polymorphism',
            'C. Dynamic polymorphism',
            'D. Non-executing polymorphism'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 74,
        question: 'A file stream refers to the flow of data between a:',
        answer: 'C. Program and file',
        options: [
            'A. Program and stream',
            'B. Program and object',
            'C. Program and file',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 75,
        question: 'When an exception is thrown, it needs to be:',
        answer: 'B. Handled appropriately',
        options: [
            'A. Executed',
            'B. Handled appropriately',
            'C. Resolved',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 76,
        question: 'C++ exception handling mechanism mainly uses how many keywords?',
        answer: 'C. Two',
        options: [
            'A. Four',
            'B. Three',
            'C. Two',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 77,
        question: 'In C++, which operator is used for dynamic memory allocation?',
        answer: 'C. new',
        options: [
            'A. Scope resolution',
            'B. Conditional',
            'C. new',
            'D. Membership access'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 78,
        question: 'Which function returns the current position of the get or put pointer in bytes?',
        answer: 'A. tellg()',
        options: [
            'A. tellg()',
            'B. tellp()',
            'C. tell()',
            'D. Both (A) and (B)'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 79,
        question: 'A pure virtual function is a virtual function that:',
        answer: 'D. Both (A) and (C)',
        options: [
            'A. has no body',
            'B. returns nothing',
            'C. is used in the base class',
            'D. Both (A) and (C)',
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 80,
        question: 'Which term means that the code associated with a given procedure call is not known until the time of the call at runtime?',
        answer: 'B. Runtime binding',
        options: [
            'A. Dynamic binding',
            'B. Runtime binding',
            'C. Early binding',
            'D. Static binding'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 81,
        question: 'Through .......... we can eliminate redundant code and extend the use of existing classes.',
        answer: 'B. Inheritance',
        options: [
            'A. Encapsulation',
            'B. Inheritance',
            'C. Polymorphism',
            'D. Overloading'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 82,
        question: 'C++ language was developed by ..............',
        answer: 'C. Bjarne Stroustrup',
        options: [
            'A. Dennis Rechard',
            'B. Dennis M. Ritchie',
            'C. Bjarne Stroustrup',
            'D. Anders Hejlsberg'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 83,
        question: 'In which year, the name of the language was changed from "C with Classes" to C++?',
        answer: 'C. 1983',
        options: [
            'A. 1979',
            'B. 1972',
            'C. 1983',
            'D. 1986'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 84,
        question: 'C++ language is a successor to which language?',
        answer: 'B. C',
        options: [
            'A. B',
            'B. C',
            'C. Java',
            'D. VB'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 85,
        question: 'C++ language is a',
        answer: 'A. Object Oriented Language',
        options: [
            'A. Object Oriented Language',
            'B. Procedural Oriented Language',
            'C. Structural Oriented Language',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 86,
        question: 'C++ follows',
        answer: 'C. Both of the above',
        options: [
            'A. Top-down Design Approach',
            'B. Bottom-up Design Approach',
            'C. Both of the above',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 87,
        question: 'C++ is a....',
        answer: 'A. High-level language',
        options: [
            'A. High-level language',
            'B. Medium level language',
            'C. Low-level language',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 88,
        question: 'How many keywords are there in C++?',
        answer: 'A. 95',
        options: [
            'A. 95',
            'B. 48',
            'C. 99',
            'D. 32'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 89,
        question: 'Which of the following is not a valid keyword in C++ language?',
        answer: 'D. do-while',
        options: [
            'A. while',
            'B. for',
            'C. switch',
            'D. do-while'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 90,
        question: 'Which of the following statements is correct about identifiers in C++?',
        answer: 'A. Identifiers are the combination of alphanumeric characters that can be used for function and variable names.',
        options: [
            'A. Identifiers are the combination of alphanumeric characters that can be used for function and variable names.',
            'B. Identifiers are a combination of alphanumeric characters that can be used for looping statements.',
            'C. Both of the above',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 91,
        question: 'Which of the following language translators is used in C++?',
        answer: 'C. Compiler',
        options: [
            'A. Assembler',
            'B. Interpreter',
            'C. Compiler',
            'D. Both Interpreter and Compiler'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 92,
        question: 'Which of the following whitespace characters can be used in C++?',
        answer: 'D. All 1, 2, 3, 4',
        options: [
            'A. 1 and 2',
            'B. 3 and 4',
            'C. 1, 3 and 4',
            'D. All 1, 2, 3, 4'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 93,
        question: 'C++ is a more secure programming language compared to language',
        answer: 'B. False',
        options: [
            'A. True',
            'B. False'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 94,
        question: 'Which of the following header file is used to define cin and cout?',
        answer: 'B. <iostream.h>',
        options: [
            'A. <iomanip.h>',
            'B. <iostream.h>',
            'C. <fstream.h>',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 95,
        question: 'The cin, cout are',
        answer: 'D. objects',
        options: [
            'A. library functions',
            'B. structures',
            'C. pointers',
            'D. objects'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 96,
        question: 'The stdout stands for',
        answer: 'B. Standard Output',
        options: [
            'A. State Output',
            'B. Standard Output',
            'C. Stand Output',
            'D. Stream Output'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 97,
        question: 'Which of the following is an insertion operator in C++?',
        answer: 'A. <<',
        options: [
            'A. <<',
            'B. >>',
            'C. <<<<',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 98,
        question: 'Which of the following is an extraction operator in C++?',
        answer: 'B. >>',
        options: [
            'A. >>>',
            'B. >>',
            'C. <<<<',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 99,
        question: 'The endl is a',
        answer: 'B. macro',
        options: [
            'A. function',
            'B. macro',
            'C. pointer',
            'D. object'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 100,
        question: 'Which of the following are types of data types in C++?',
        answer: 'C. 1, 2 and 3',
        options: [
            'A. 1 and 2',
            'B. 1, 2 and 4',
            'C. 1, 2 and 3',
            'D. All 1, 2, 3, 4'
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 101,
        "question": "In object oriented programming, the program is divided into",
        "answer": "a) Class",
        "options": [
            "a) Class",
            "b) Object",
            "c) Function",
            "d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 102,
        "question": "Which one is the Object Oriented Programming language?",
        "answer": "c) C++",
        "options": [
            "a) Cobol",
            "b) C",
            "c) C++",
            "d) Both C & C++"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 103,
        "question": "The wrapping up of data and functions into a single unit is called",
        "answer": "b) Encapsulation",
        "options": [
            "a) Inheritance",
            "b) Encapsulation",
            "c) Data hiding",
            "d) Polymorphism"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 104,
        "question": "The process by which objects of one class acquire the properties of objects of another class is called",
        "answer": "b) Inheritance",
        "options": [
            "a) Abstraction",
            "b) Inheritance",
            "c) Encapsulation",
            "d) Polymorphism"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 105,
        "question": "In OOP, which concept provides the idea of reusability?",
        "answer": "a) Inheritance",
        "options": [
            "a) Inheritance",
            "b) Encapsulation",
            "c) Data hiding",
            "d) Polymorphism"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 106,
        "question": "The process of making an operator to exhibit different behaviors in different instances is called",
        "answer": "b) Operator overloading",
        "options": [
            "a) Function overloading",
            "b) Operator overloading",
            "c) Inheritance",
            "d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 107,
        "question": "The process of making a function to exhibit different behaviors in different instances is called",
        "answer": "a) Function overloading",
        "options": [
            "a) Function overloading",
            "b) Operator overloading",
            "c) Inheritance",
            "d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 108,
        "question": "Objects communicate with one another by using",
        "answer": "a) Message passing",
        "options": [
            "a) Message passing",
            "b) Operator overloading",
            "c) Inheritance",
            "d) Both (a) & (b)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 109,
        "question": "Through ____ we can eliminate redundant code and extend the use of an existing class.",
        "answer": "a) Inheritance",
        "options": [
            "a) Inheritance",
            "b) Operator overloading",
            "c) Encapsulation",
            "d) Both (a) & (b)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 110,
        "question": "The principle that helps the programmer to build secure programs is",
        "answer": "b) Encapsulation",
        "options": [
            "a) Operator overloading",
            "b) Encapsulation",
            "c) Data hiding",
            "d) Polymorphism"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 111,
        "question": "What are the basic run time entities in an object oriented program?",
        "answer": "a) Objects",
        "options": [
            "a) Objects",
            "b) Functions",
            "c) Data",
            "d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 112,
        "question": "OOPs follows _____ approach during program design.",
        "answer": "b) Bottom-up",
        "options": [
            "a) Top down",
            "b) Bottom-up",
            "c) Both (a) and (b)",
            "d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 113,
        "question": "The technique of hiding internal details in an object is called",
        "answer": "a) Encapsulation",
        "options": [
            "a) Encapsulation",
            "b) Functions",
            "c) Abstraction",
            "d) Inheritance"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 114,
        "question": "Classes are ______ data type.",
        "answer": "b) User-defined",
        "options": [
            "a) Derived",
            "b) User-defined",
            "c) Built-in",
            "d) Both (a) & (c)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 115,
        "question": "______ provides an interface between the object's data and the program.",
        "answer": "b) Functions",
        "options": [
            "a) Object",
            "b) Functions",
            "c) Class",
            "d) Polymorphism"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 116,
        "question": "______ refers to the linking of procedure call to the code to be executed in response to the call.",
        "answer": "c) Dynamic binding",
        "options": [
            "a) Polymorphism",
            "b) Functions",
            "c) Dynamic binding",
            "d) Object"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 117,
        "question": "An operator that is a request for an object is called ______.",
        "answer": "d) Message passing",
        "options": [
            "a) Object",
            "b) Functions",
            "c) Dynamic binding",
            "d) Message passing"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 118,
        "question": "The << operator is known as",
        "answer": "c) Insertion",
        "options": [
            "a) Put to",
            "b) Get from",
            "c) Insertion",
            "d) Both (a) & (c)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 119,
        "question": "The >> operator is known as",
        "answer": "c) Extraction",
        "options": [
            "a) Put to",
            "b) Get from",
            "c) Extraction",
            "d) Both (b) & (c)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 120,
        "question": "___ contains function prototypes for the standard input and output functions.",
        "answer": "b) iostream.h",
        "options": [
            "a) iomanip.h",
            "b) iostream.h",
            "c) stdlib.h",
            "d) Both (a) & (c)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 121,
        "question": "In C++, the default return type for all functions is",
        "answer": "a) int",
        "options": [
            "a) int",
            "b) void",
            "c) float",
            "d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 122,
        "question": "The multiple use of input and output operators is called",
        "answer": "c) Cascading",
        "options": [
            "a) Polymorphism",
            "b) Inheritance",
            "c) Cascading",
            "d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 123,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a feature of OOPS?",
        "answer": "d) None of these",
        "options": [
            "a) Polymorphism",
            "b) Inheritance",
            "c) Dynamic binding",
            "d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 124,
        "question": "By default, the members of a C++ class are",
        "answer": "a) Private",
        "options": [
            "a) Private",
            "b) Public",
            "c) Protected",
            "d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 125,
        "question": "Which of the following functions must contain in all C++ programs?",
        "answer": "c) main()",
        "options": [
            "a) start()",
            "b) system()",
            "c) main()",
            "d) program()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 126,
        "question": "Which one of the following is the correct operator to compare two values?",
        "answer": "d) ==",
        "options": [
            "a) <",
            "b) >",
            "c) Equal",
            "d) =="
        ]
    },

    {
        "numb": 127,
        "question": "C++ is originally developed by",
        "answer": "c) Bjarne Stroustrup",
        "options": [
            "a) Nicolas Wirth",
            "b) Dennis Ritchie",
            "c) Bjarne Stroustrup",
            "d) Ken Thompson"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 128,
        "question": "Identify the unary operator",
        "answer": "b) ++",
        "options": [
            "a) +",
            "b) ++",
            "c) -",
            "d) %"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 129,
        "question": "______ are used to check the relationship between two numeric operands or expressions.",
        "answer": "b) Relational operators",
        "options": [
            "a) Logical operators",
            "b) Relational operators",
            "c) Arithmetic operators",
            "d) Bitwise operators"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 130,
        "question": "______ is a function that is expanded in line when it is invoked.",
        "answer": "c) Inline function",
        "options": [
            "a) Library function",
            "b) User-defined function",
            "c) Inline function",
            "d) None of these"
        ]
    },

    {
        "numb": 131,
        "question": "The qualifier 'const' in C++ tells the compiler that the function should",
        "answer": "a) Const",
        "options": [
            "a) Const",
            "b) Static",
            "c) Constant",
            "d) Inline"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 132,
        "question": "______ refers to the use of the same thing for different purposes.",
        "answer": "b) Overloading",
        "options": [
            "a) Function declaration",
            "b) Overloading",
            "c) Function calling",
            "d) Prototyping"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 133,
        "question": "The functions declared inside the class are known as",
        "answer": "c) Member functions",
        "options": [
            "a) Data members",
            "b) Library functions",
            "c) Member functions",
            "d) User defined functions"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 134,
        "question": "Calling a member function by using its name from another member function of the same class is known as",
        "answer": "c) Nesting of member function",
        "options": [
            "a) Grouping of member function",
            "b) Member function group",
            "c) Nesting of member function",
            "d) Nested group of member function"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 135,
        "question": "______ function can only be called by another function that is a member of its class.",
        "answer": "b) Private member function",
        "options": [
            "a) Member function",
            "b) Private member function",
            "c) Nested member function",
            "d) Public member function"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 136,
        "question": "______ are normally used to maintain values common to the entire class.",
        "answer": "b) Static variables",
        "options": [
            "a) Dynamic variables",
            "b) Static variables",
            "c) Private variables",
            "d) Public variables"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 137,
        "question": "A static variable is initialized to ______ when the first object of its class is created.",
        "answer": "c) 0",
        "options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) Null",
            "c) 0",
            "d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 138,
        "question": "A function calling itself is called",
        "answer": "d) Recursion",
        "options": [
            "a) Inline function",
            "b) Static function",
            "c) Friend function",
            "d) Recursion"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 139,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a type of constructor?",
        "answer": "b) Friend constructor",
        "options": [
            "a) Copy constructor",
            "b) Friend constructor",
            "c) Default constructor",
            "d) Parameterized constructor"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 140,
        "question": "Constructor is executed when",
        "answer": "a) An object is created",
        "options": [
            "a) An object is created",
            "b) An object is used",
            "c) A class is declared",
            "d) An object goes out of scope"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 141,
        "question": "Which of the following is also known as an instance of a class?",
        "answer": "b) Object",
        "options": [
            "a) Friend functions",
            "b) Object",
            "c) Member functions",
            "d) Member"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 142,
        "question": "A constructor that accepts constructor parameters is called",
        "answer": "d) Parameterized constructor",
        "options": [
            "a) One",
            "b) Two",
            "c) No",
            "d) Parameterized constructor"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 143,
        "question": "Destructor has the same name as the constructor and is preceded by",
        "answer": "b) ~",
        "options": [
            "a) +",
            "b) ~",
            "c) -",
            "d) !"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 144,
        "question": "Which constructor function is designed to copy objects of the same class type?",
        "answer": "d) Copy constructor",
        "options": [
            "a) Create constructor",
            "b) Object constructor",
            "c) Dynamic constructor",
            "d) Copy constructor"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 145,
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
        "answer": "a) A constructor has the same name as the class in which it is present",
        "options": [
            "a) A constructor has the same name as the class in which it is present",
            "b) A constructor has a different name than the class in which it is present",
            "c) A constructor always returns an integer",
            "d) A constructor cannot be overloaded"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 146,
        "question": "A destructor takes ____ arguments.",
        "answer": "d) No",
        "options": [
            "a) One",
            "b) Two",
            "c) Three",
            "d) No"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 147,
        "question": "Destructor calls are made in which order of the corresponding constructor call?",
        "answer": "a) Reverse order",
        "options": [
            "a) Reverse order",
            "b) Forward order",
            "c) Depends on how the object is constructed",
            "d) Depends on how many objects are constructed"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 148,
        "question": "Which allows you to create a derived class that inherits properties from more than one base class?",
        "answer": "c) Hybrid inheritance",
        "options": [
            "a) Multilevel inheritance",
            "b) Multiple inheritance",
            "c) Hybrid inheritance",
            "d) Hierarchical inheritance"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 149,
        "question": "A derived class with only one base class is",
        "answer": "c) Single inheritance",
        "options": [
            "a) Multilevel inheritance",
            "b) Multiple inheritance",
            "c) Single inheritance",
            "d) Hierarchical inheritance"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 150,
        "question": "The duplication of inherited members due to multiple paths can be avoided by making a common base class is called",
        "answer": "b) Virtual base class",
        "options": [
            "a) Abstract class",
            "b) Virtual base class",
            "c) Multiple inheritance",
            "d) Nesting of classes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 151,
        "question": "The operators that can't be overloaded are",
        "answer": "c) Ternary operator",
        "options": [
            "a) Binary operators",
            "b) Unary operators",
            "c) Ternary operator",
            "d) None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 152,
        "question": "A friend function for unary operator overloading takes ____ arguments.",
        "answer": "a) Zero",
        "options": [
            "a) Zero",
            "b) One",
            "c) Two",
            "d) None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 153,
        "question": "A friend function for binary operator overloading takes ____ arguments.",
        "answer": "c) Two",
        "options": [
            "a) Zero",
            "b) One",
            "c) Two",
            "d) None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 154,
        "question": "The variable that contains the address of a constant or variable is",
        "answer": "c) Pointer",
        "options": [
            "a) Function",
            "b) Array",
            "c) Pointer",
            "d) Structure"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 155,
        "question": "The memory management operators in C++ are",
        "answer": "a) New & delete",
        "options": [
            "a) New & delete",
            "b) Malloc",
            "c) Calloc",
            "d) Free"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 156,
        "question": "The pointer that refers to the object that has called the member function currently is",
        "answer": "a) This",
        "options": [
            "a) This",
            "b) Address",
            "c) Virtual function",
            "d) None"
        ]
    },

    {
        "numb": 157,
        "question": "The empty virtual functions are called",
        "answer": "a) Pure virtual functions",
        "options": [
            "a) Pure virtual functions",
            "b) Virtual table",
            "c) Polymorphism",
            "d) Virtual base class"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 158,
        "question": "A stream of bytes that is the interface between IO and IO devices is",
        "answer": "d) File",
        "options": [
            "a) Streams",
            "b) Class",
            "c) Object",
            "d) File"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 159,
        "question": "The class that is derived from the standard library ios containing input functions is",
        "answer": "a) ios::istream",
        "options": [
            "a) ios::istream",
            "b) Kistream",
            "c) Stream",
            "d) ostream"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 160,
        "question": "The class that is derived from the standard library ios containing output functions is",
        "answer": "d) ostream",
        "options": [
            "a) ios",
            "b) ostosain",
            "c) stream",
            "d) ostream"
        ]
    },

    {
        "numb": 161,
        "question": "Which function is in the ostream class?",
        "answer": "c) write",
        "options": [
            "a) get()",
            "b) read()",
            "c) write",
            "d) cin"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 162,
        "question": "Which function is in the istream class?",
        "answer": "a) get()",
        "options": [
            "a) get()",
            "b) put()",
            "c) write",
            "d) cout"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 163,
        "question": "The standard library inherited from istream & ostream is:",
        "answer": "b) iostream",
        "options": [
            "a) ios",
            "b) iostream",
            "c) ifstream",
            "d) ofstream"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 164,
        "question": "The function used to receive one character at a time:",
        "answer": "a) get()",
        "options": [
            "a) get()",
            "b) put()",
            "c) getline()",
            "d) write()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 165,
        "question": "The function used to display one character at a time:",
        "answer": "b) put()",
        "options": [
            "a) get()",
            "b) put()",
            "c) getline()",
            "d) write()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 166,
        "question": "The function used to receive one line at a time:",
        "answer": "c) getline()",
        "options": [
            "a) get()",
            "b) put()",
            "c) getline()",
            "d) write()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 167,
        "question": "The function used to display one line at a time:",
        "answer": "d) write()",
        "options": [
            "a) get()",
            "b) put()",
            "c) getline()",
            "d) write()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 168,
        "question": "___ are the reserved words of the programming language:",
        "answer": "d) Keywords",
        "options": [
            "a) Tokens",
            "b) Literals",
            "c) Separators",
            "d) Keywords"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 169,
        "question": "___ refer to the names of variables, functions, arrays, classes:",
        "answer": "a) Identifiers",
        "options": [
            "a) Identifiers",
            "b) Operators",
            "c) Punctuators",
            "d) Manipulators"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 170,
        "question": "Write the range of value of the data type 'char':",
        "answer": "b) 0 to 255",
        "options": [
            "a) 0 to 128",
            "b) 0 to 255",
            "c) 255 to 255",
            "d) -128 to 127"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 171,
        "question": "A ___ is the name of a storage location:",
        "answer": "b) Variable",
        "options": [
            "a) Identifier",
            "b) Variable",
            "c) Keyword",
            "d) Token"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 172,
        "question": "Array indexing always starts with the number:",
        "answer": "a) 0",
        "options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 10"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 173,
        "question": "We declare a function with ___ if it does not have any return type:",
        "answer": "c) void",
        "options": [
            "a) Long",
            "b) Double",
            "c) Void",
            "d) Int"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 174,
        "question": "Which of the following is a selection statement in C++?",
        "answer": "d) switch",
        "options": [
            "a) break",
            "b) goto",
            "c) exit",
            "d) switch"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 175,
        "question": "Which of the following is a correct comment?",
        "answer": "c) /* Comment */",
        "options": [
            "a) \"/Comments/\"",
            "b) *Comment*",
            "c) \"/* Comment */\"",
            "d) (Comment)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 176,
        "question": "To increase the value of c by one, which of the following statements is correct?",
        "answer": "d) c += 1",
        "options": [
            "a) c++:",
            "b) c = c + 1:",
            "c) c + 1 -> c",
            "d) c += 1"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 177,
        "question": "When the following piece of code is executed, what happens? b = 3; a = b++;",
        "answer": "a) A contains 3 and b contains 4",
        "options": [
            "a) A contains 3 and b contains 4",
            "b) A contains 4 and b contains 4",
            "c) A contains 4 and b contains 3",
            "d) A contains 3 and b contains 3"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 178,
        "question": "How many times is a do-while loop guaranteed to loop?",
        "answer": "c) 1",
        "options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) Infinitely",
            "c) 1",
            "d) variable"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 179,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a valid relational operator?",
        "answer": "a) =>",
        "options": [
            "a) =>",
            "b) ==",
            "c) >=",
            "d) <="
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 180,
        "question": "Strings are character arrays. The last index of it contains the null-terminated character:",
        "answer": "c) \\0",
        "options": [
            "a) in",
            "b) it",
            "c) \\0",
            "d) 11"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 181,
        "question": "What will be the values of x, m, and n after the execution of the following statements?\nint x, m, n; m = 10; n = 15; x = ++m + n++;",
        "answer": "b) x = 26, m = 11, n = 16",
        "options": [
            "a) x = 25, m = 10, n = 15",
            "b) x = 26, m = 11, n = 16",
            "c) x = 27, m = 11, n = 16",
            "d) x = 27, m = 10, n = 15"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 182,
        "question": "Consider the following statements:\nint x = 22, y = 15;\nx = (x > y) ? 2*(x+y) : (x-y);\nWhat will be the value of x after executing these statements?",
        "answer": "b) 37",
        "options": [
            "a) 22",
            "b) 37",
            "c) 7",
            "d) Error, cannot be executed"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 183,
        "question": "Which of the following keywords is used to control access to a class member?",
        "answer": "c) Protected",
        "options": [
            "a) Default",
            "b) Break",
            "c) Protected",
            "d) Asm"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 184,
        "question": "Which of the following means 'The use of an object of one class in the definition of another class'?",
        "answer": "c) Composition",
        "options": [
            "a) Encapsulation",
            "b) Inheritance",
            "c) Composition",
            "d) Abstraction"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 185,
        "question": "A derived class is also called a:",
        "answer": "b) Subclass",
        "options": [
            "a) Small class",
            "b) Subclass",
            "c) Noticeable class",
            "d) Big class"
        ]
    },

    {
        "numb": 186,
        "question": "Which of these inheritance is shown in case we inherit some base class from another class, then one of the classes derives it?",
        "answer": "c) Multilevel inheritance",
        "options": [
            "a) Single inheritance",
            "b) Multiple inheritance",
            "c) Multilevel inheritance",
            "d) Hierarchical inheritance"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 87,
        "question": "___ is the universal handler class for exceptions.",
        "answer": "c) Exceptions",
        "options": [
            "a) Maths",
            "b) Object",
            "c) Exceptions",
            "d) Errors"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 188,
        "question": "Conversion of data type is called:",
        "answer": "b) Type casting",
        "options": [
            "a) Self referencing",
            "b) Type casting",
            "c) Virtual function",
            "d) Abstract class"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 189,
        "question": "The function contained in the ios class to set width is:",
        "answer": "a) width()",
        "options": [
            "a) width()",
            "b) precision()",
            "c) fill()",
            "d) setf()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 190,
        "question": "The function contained in the class iomanip to set width is:",
        "answer": "a) setw()",
        "options": [
            "a) setw()",
            "b) set precision()",
            "c) set fill()",
            "d) setiosflags()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 191,
        "question": "How many default constructors per class are possible?",
        "answer": "a) Only one",
        "options": [
            "a) Only one",
            "b) Two",
            "c) Three",
            "d) Unlimited"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 192,
        "question": "How many times is a constructor called in the lifetime of an object?",
        "answer": "d) Depends on the way of creation of object",
        "options": [
            "a) Only once",
            "b) Twice",
            "c) Thrice",
            "d) Depends on the way of creation of object"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 193,
        "question": "The mechanism of deriving one base class with more than one derived classes is:",
        "answer": "b) Multiple inheritance",
        "options": [
            "a) Multilevel inheritance",
            "b) Multiple inheritance",
            "c) Hybrid inheritance",
            "d) Hierarchical inheritance"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 194,
        "question": "Which of the following is not correct?",
        "answer": "b) The overloaded operator must have at least one operand",
        "options": [
            "a) Only existing operators can be overloaded",
            "b) The overloaded operator must have at least one operand",
            "c) We can change the base meaning of the overloaded operators while keeping the syntax of overloaded operators",
            "d) The syntax of overloaded operators must be followed"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 195,
        "question": "A member function for unary operator overloading takes ___ arguments.",
        "answer": "a) Zero",
        "options": [
            "a) Zero",
            "b) One",
            "c) Two",
            "d) None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 196,
        "question": "Which of the following function/type of function cannot be overloaded?",
        "answer": "c) Virtual function",
        "options": [
            "a) Member function",
            "b) Static function",
            "c) Virtual function",
            "d) Both (b) and (c)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 197,
        "question": "Copy constructor must receive its arguments by:",
        "answer": "b) Only pass-by-reference",
        "options": [
            "a) Either pass-by-value or pass-by-reference",
            "b) Only pass-by-reference",
            "c) Only pass-by-value",
            "d) Only pass by address"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 198,
        "question": "The break statement causes an exit:",
        "answer": "d) From the innermost loop or switch",
        "options": [
            "a) From the innermost loop only",
            "b) Only from the innermost switch",
            "c) From all loops & switches",
            "d) From the innermost loop or switch"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 199,
        "question": "The arrays of variables that are of the type class:",
        "answer": "a) Array of objects",
        "options": [
            "a) Array of objects",
            "b) Pointer",
            "c) Object",
            "d) Structure"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 200,
        "question": "Which of the following types of data member can be shared by all instances of its class?",
        "answer": "c) Static",
        "options": [
            "a) Public",
            "b) Inherited",
            "c) Static",
            "d) Friend"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 201,
        "question": "Which is not a feature of OOP in general definitions?",
        "answer": "D. Duplicate/Redundant data",
        "options": [
            "A. Efficient Code",
            "B. Code reusability",
            "C. Modularity",
            "D. Duplicate/Redundant data"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 202,
        "question": "When OOP concept did first came into picture?",
        "answer": "C. 1970's",
        "options": [
            "A. 1980's",
            "B. 1995",
            "C. 1970's",
            "D. 1993"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 203,
        "question": "Why Java is Partially OOP language?",
        "answer": "B. It supports usual declaration of primitive data types",
        "options": [
            "A. It allows code to be written outside classes",
            "B. It supports usual declaration of primitive data types",
            "C. It does not support pointers",
            "D. It doesn't support all types of inheritance"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 204,
        "question": "Which among the following doesn't come under OOP concept?",
        "answer": "C. Platform independent",
        "options": [
            "A. Data hiding",
            "B. Message passing",
            "C. Platform independent",
            "D. Data binding"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 205,
        "question": "Which among the following, for a pure OOP language, is true?",
        "answer": "C. The language must follow all the rules of OOP",
        "options": [
            "A. The language should follow at least 1 feature of OOP",
            "B. The language must follow only 3 features of OOP",
            "C. The language must follow all the rules of OOP",
            "D. The language should follow 3 or more features of OOP"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 206,
        "question": "In multilevel inheritance, which is the most significant feature of OOP used?",
        "answer": "D. Code reusability",
        "options": [
            "A. Code efficiency",
            "B. Code readability",
            "C. Flexibility",
            "D. Code reusability"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 207,
        "question": "What is encapsulation in OOP?",
        "answer": "A. It is a way of combining various data members and member functions that operate on those data members into a single unit",
        "options": [
            "A. It is a way of combining various data members and member functions that operate on those data members into a single unit",
            "B. It is a way of combining various data members and member functions into a single unit which can operate on any data",
            "C. It is a way of combining various data members into a single unit",
            "D. It is a way of combining various member functions into a single unit"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 208,
        "question": "Which of the following is not true about polymorphism?",
        "answer": "B. Increases overhead of function definition always",
        "options": [
            "A. Helps in redefining the same functionality",
            "B. Increases overhead of function definition always",
            "C. It is feature of OOP",
            "D. Ease in readability of program"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 209,
        "question": "Which constructor will be called from the object created in the below C++ code?\n\nclass A {\n int i;\n A() { i=0; cout << i; }\n A(int x=0) { i=x; cout << i; }\n}\nA obj1;",
        "answer": "D. Compile time error",
        "options": [
            "A. Parameterized constructor",
            "B. Default constructor",
            "C. Run time error",
            "D. Compile time error"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 210,
        "question": "What is an abstraction in object-oriented programming?",
        "answer": "A. Hiding the implementation and showing only the features",
        "options": [
            "A. Hiding the implementation and showing only the features",
            "B. Hiding the important data",
            "C. Hiding the implementation",
            "D. Showing the important data"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 211,
        "question": "Single level inheritance supports",
        "answer": "D. Runtime",
        "options": [
            "A. Language independency",
            "B. Multiple inheritance",
            "C. Compile time",
            "D. Runtime"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 212,
        "question": "What is an object in C++?",
        "answer": "B. A variable",
        "options": [
            "A. A function",
            "B. A variable",
            "C. A data type",
            "D. A structure"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 213,
        "question": "What is information hiding in OOP?",
        "answer": "A. Hiding implementation details of an object from the user",
        "options": [
            "A. Hiding implementation details of an object from the user",
            "B. Hiding data members of a class from the user",
            "C. Hiding member functions of a class from the user",
            "D. Hiding the main function from the user"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 214,
        "question": "Where is the memory allocated for the objects?",
        "answer": "D. RAM",
        "options": [
            "A. Cache",
            "B. ROM",
            "C. HDD",
            "D. RAM"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 215,
        "question": "Which access specifier is used when no access specifier is used with a member of class (Java)?",
        "answer": "B. Default",
        "options": [
            "A. Private",
            "B. Default",
            "C. Protected",
            "D. Public"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 216,
        "question": "Which among the following is false?",
        "answer": "C. Default members can't be inherited",
        "options": [
            "A. Private members can be accessed using friend functions",
            "B. Member functions can be made private",
            "C. Default members can't be inherited",
            "D. Public members are accessible from other classes also"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 217,
        "question": "If class A has add() function with protected access, and few other members in public. Then class B inherits class A privately. Will the user will not be able to call from the object of class B.",
        "answer": "D. Private, protected and public members of class A",
        "options": [
            "A. Any function of class A",
            "B. The add() function of class A",
            "C. Any member of class A",
            "D. Private, protected and public members of class A"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 218,
        "question": "If class B inherits class A privately. And class B has a friend function. Will the friend function be able to access the private member of class A?",
        "answer": "C. No, because friend function can only access private members of friend class",
        "options": [
            "A. Yes because friend function can access all the members",
            "B. Yes, because friend function is of class B",
            "C. No, because friend function can only access private members of friend class",
            "D. No, because friend function can access private member of class A also"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 219,
        "question": "If an abstract class has all the private members, then",
        "answer": "A. No class will be able to implement members of abstract class",
        "options": [
            "A. No class will be able to implement members of abstract class",
            "B. Only single inheritance class can implement its members",
            "C. Only other enclosing classes will be able to implement those members",
            "D. No class will be able to access those members but can implement"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 220,
        "question": "Which specifier should be used for member functions of a class?",
        "answer": "D. Public",
        "options": [
            "A. Private",
            "B. Default",
            "C. Protected",
            "D. Public"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 221,
        "question": "Which of the following is not type of class?",
        "answer": "C. Start Class",
        "options": [
            "A. Abstract Class",
            "B. Final Class",
            "C. Start Class",
            "D. String Class"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 222,
        "question": "Class is pass by",
        "answer": "B. Reference",
        "options": [
            "A. Value",
            "B. Reference",
            "C. Value or Reference, depending on program",
            "D. Copy"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 223,
        "question": "Which is most appropriate comment on following class definition?\n\nclass Student {\n int a;\n public: float a;\n}",
        "answer": "A. Error: same variable name can't be used twice",
        "options": [
            "A. Error: same variable name can't be used twice",
            "B. Error: Public must come first",
            "C. Error: data types are different for same variable",
            "D. It is correct"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 224,
        "question": "Size of a class is",
        "answer": "D. Classes doesn't have any size",
        "options": [
            "A. Sum of the size of all the variables declared inside the class",
            "B. Sum of the size of all the variables along with inherited variables in the class",
            "C. Size of the largest size of variable",
            "D. Classes doesn't have any size"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 225,
        "question": "Which among the following is false, for a member function of a class?",
        "answer": "C. Member functions need not be declared inside the class definition",
        "options": [
            "A. All member functions must be defined",
            "B. Member functions can be defined inside or outside the class body",
            "C. Member functions need not be declared inside the class definition",
            "D. Member functions can be made friend to another class using the friend keyword"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 226,
        "question": "Which syntax for class definition is wrong?",
        "answer": "B. student class()",
        "options": [
            "A. class student()",
            "B. student class()",
            "C. class student { public: student(int a){} }",
            "D. class student { student(int a){} }"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 227,
        "question": "Which of the following pairs are similar?",
        "answer": "B. Class and structure",
        "options": [
            "A. Class and object",
            "B. Class and structure",
            "C. Structure and object",
            "D. Structure and functions"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 228,
        "question": "Instance of which type of class can't be created?",
        "answer": "D. Abstract class",
        "options": [
            "A. Anonymous class",
            "B. Nested class",
            "C. Parent class",
            "D. Abstract class"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 229,
        "question": "Which type of data can a local class access from the function in which it is defined?",
        "answer": "A. Static and extern",
        "options": [
            "A. Static and extern",
            "B. Abstract and static",
            "C. Void and extern",
            "D. Const and static"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 230,
        "question": "Local classes can access the type names and enumerators defined by the enclosing function.",
        "answer": "A. True",
        "options": [
            "A. True",
            "B. False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 231,
        "question": "All the member functions of local classes are _____ by default.",
        "answer": "C. Abstract",
        "options": [
            "A. Static",
            "B. Inline",
            "C. Abstract",
            "D. Virtual"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 232,
        "question": "How many local classes can be defined inside a single function?",
        "answer": "D. As many as required",
        "options": [
            "A. Only 1",
            "B. Only 3",
            "C. Only 5",
            "D. As many as required"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 233,
        "question": "All the data members of a local class must be",
        "answer": "B. Defined in constructor",
        "options": [
            "A. Defined with declaration",
            "B. Defined in constructor",
            "C. Declared and defined in constructor",
            "D. Declared using a member function"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 234,
        "question": "What is the scope of a local class?",
        "answer": "B. Within the function",
        "options": [
            "A. Within the class only",
            "B. Within the function",
            "C. Within the program",
            "D. One time creation and live till end of program"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 235,
        "question": "Which among the following is the main advantage of using local classes?",
        "answer": "C. Helps to add extra functionality to a function",
        "options": [
            "A. Make program more efficient",
            "B. Makes program execution faster",
            "C. Helps to add extra functionality to a function",
            "D. Helps to add more members to a function"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 236,
        "question": "A static nested class is nested in another class in behavior that is _____ class.",
        "answer": "A. Top level, top level",
        "options": [
            "A. Top level, top level",
            "B. Top level, low level",
            "C. Low level, top level",
            "D. Low level, low level"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 237,
        "question": "Which among the following best describes destructor?",
        "answer": "A. A function which is called just before the objects are destroyed",
        "options": [
            "A. A function which is called just before the objects are destroyed",
            "B. A function which is called after each reference to the object",
            "C. A function which is called after termination of the program",
            "D. A function which is called before calling any member function"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 238,
        "question": "Which among the following is correct syntax for the destructors?",
        "answer": "C. ~classname()",
        "options": [
            "A. classname()",
            "B. ()classname",
            "C. ~classname()",
            "D. -classname()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 239,
        "question": "Destructor calls",
        "answer": "C. Can be implicit or explicit",
        "options": [
            "A. Are only implicit",
            "B. Are only explicit",
            "C. Can be implicit or explicit",
            "D. Are made at end of program only"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 240,
        "question": "Number of destructors called are",
        "answer": "A. Always equal to number of constructors called",
        "options": [
            "A. Always equal to number of constructors called",
            "B. Always less than the number of constructors called",
            "C. Always greater than the number of constructors called",
            "D. Always less than or equal to number of constructors"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 241,
        "question": "The destructor can be called before the constructor if required",
        "answer": "B. False",
        "options": [
            "A. True",
            "B. False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 242,
        "question": "The constructor",
        "answer": "D. Doesn't have a return type",
        "options": [
            "A. Have a return type",
            "B. May have a return type",
            "C. Of derived classes have return type",
            "D. Doesn't have a return type"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 243,
        "question": "Which among the following is correct for abstract class destructors?",
        "answer": "A. It doesn't have destructors",
        "options": [
            "A. It doesn't have destructors",
            "B. It has destructors",
            "C. It may or may not have destructors",
            "D. It contains an implicit destructor"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 244,
        "question": "How the constructors and destructors can be differentiated?",
        "answer": "C. Destructors are preceded with a tilde (~) symbol, constructor doesn't",
        "options": [
            "A. Destructor have a return type but constructor doesn't",
            "B. Destructors can't be defined by the programmer, constructors can be defined",
            "C. Destructors are preceded with a tilde (~) symbol, constructor doesn't",
            "D. Destructors are same as constructors in syntax"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 245,
        "question": "Destructors can be",
        "answer": "B. Virtual",
        "options": [
            "A. Abstract type",
            "B. Virtual",
            "C. Void",
            "D. Any type depending on situation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 246,
        "question": "When is it advised to have user defined destructor?",
        "answer": "A. When class contains some pointer to memory allocated class",
        "options": [
            "A. When class contains some pointer to memory allocated class",
            "B. When a class contains static variables",
            "C. When a class contains static functions",
            "D. When a class is inheriting another class only"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 247,
        "question": "Which among the following is correct for the destructor concept?",
        "answer": "D. There can be only one destructor in a class",
        "options": [
            "A. Destructors can be overloaded",
            "B. Destructors can have only one parameter at maximum",
            "C. Destructors are always called after object goes out of scope",
            "D. There can be only one destructor in a class"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 248,
        "question": "When an object is passed to a function, its copy is made in the function and then",
        "answer": "A. The destructor of the copy is called when function is returned",
        "options": [
            "A. The destructor of the copy is called when function is returned",
            "B. The destructor is never called in this case",
            "C. The destructor is called but it is always implicit",
            "D. The destructor must be user defined"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 249,
        "question": "In how many ways can an object be passed to a function?",
        "answer": "B. 2",
        "options": [
            "A. 1",
            "B. 2",
            "C. 3",
            "D. 4"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 250,
        "question": "If an object is passed by address, will the constructor be called?",
        "answer": "C. No, values are copied",
        "options": [
            "A. Yes, to allocate the memory",
            "B. Yes, to initialize the members",
            "C. No, values are copied",
            "D. No, temporary object is created"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 251,
        "question": "Passing an object using copy constructor and pass by value are same",
        "answer": "B. False",
        "options": [
            "A. True",
            "B. False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 252,
        "question": "Whenever an object is assigned to a variable or passed to a method",
        "answer": "A. Actually the objects aren't used",
        "options": [
            "A. Actually the objects aren't used",
            "B. Actually only the objects are used",
            "C. Actually a pointer to an object is used",
            "D. Actually copy of object is used"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 253,
        "question": "Can a super class object give reference to a subclass method?",
        "answer": "A. No, it is not possible",
        "options": [
            "A. No, it is not possible",
            "B. Maybe, it is possible",
            "C. No, it's not possible",
            "D. No, it's not possible in few cases only"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 254,
        "question": "If a reference variable is declared final then",
        "answer": "A. It can never be reassigned to refer to a different object",
        "options": [
            "A. It can never be reassigned to refer to a different object",
            "B. It can be assigned to refer to any object anytime",
            "C. It can never be assigned with any object",
            "D. It can be assigned with 2 or more objects simultaneously"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 255,
        "question": "Invoking a method on a particular object is sending a message to that object.",
        "answer": "B. Same as",
        "options": [
            "A. Different from",
            "B. Same as",
            "C. Somewhat similar",
            "D. Part of"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 256,
        "question": "When is the memory allocated for an object?",
        "answer": "C. When object constructor is called",
        "options": [
            "A. At declaration of object",
            "B. At compile time",
            "C. When object constructor is called",
            "D. When object is initialized to another object"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 257,
        "question": "The memory allocated for an object",
        "answer": "C. Can be static or dynamic",
        "options": [
            "A. Can be only dynamic",
            "B. Can be only static",
            "C. Can be static or dynamic",
            "D. Can't be done using dynamic functions"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 258,
        "question": "In Java, _____ takes care of managing memory for objects dynamically",
        "answer": "D. Garbage collector",
        "options": [
            "A. Free collector",
            "B. Dust collector",
            "C. Memory manager",
            "D. Garbage collector"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 259,
        "question": "How can the objects of array be denoted?",
        "answer": "A. Indices",
        "options": [
            "A. Indices",
            "B. Name",
            "C. Random numbers",
            "D. Alphabets"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 260,
        "question": "The objects in an object array,",
        "answer": "B. Can be created without calling default constructor",
        "options": [
            "A. Can be created without use of constructor",
            "B. Can be created without calling default constructor",
            "C. Can't be created with use of constructor",
            "D. Can't be created without calling default constructor"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 261,
        "question": "Immutable objects are used,",
        "answer": "A. To set up as a fixed state",
        "options": [
            "A. To set up as a fixed state",
            "B. To set up variable object",
            "C. To set up an object of abstract class",
            "D. To set up an object of derived class"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 262,
        "question": "Objects can be used",
        "answer": "B. To access only public members of a class",
        "options": [
            "A. To access any member of a class",
            "B. To access only public members of a class",
            "C. To access only protected members of a class",
            "D. To access only private members of a class"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 263,
        "question": "A single object can be used",
        "answer": "C. As only one class type at a time",
        "options": [
            "A. As only two class types at a time",
            "B. As only three class types at a time",
            "C. As only one class type at a time",
            "D. As of as many class types as required"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 264,
        "question": "Abstract classes can instances.",
        "answer": "A. Never have",
        "options": [
            "A. Never have",
            "B. Always have",
            "C. Have array of",
            "D. Have pointer of"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 265,
        "question": "Which among the following is the proper syntax for the template class?",
        "answer": "C. template <typename T> T named(T x, T y)()",
        "options": [
            "A. template<typename T1, typename T2>;",
            "B. Template <typename T1, typename T2>;",
            "C. template <typename T> T named(T x, T y)()",
            "D. Template <typename T1, typename T2> T1 named (T1 x, T2 y)()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 266,
        "question": "What are the two specializations of I/O template classes in C++?",
        "answer": "B. 8-bit character and wide characters",
        "options": [
            "A. 16-bit character and wide characters",
            "B. 8-bit character and wide characters",
            "C. 32-bit character and locale characters",
            "D. 64-bit characters and locale characters"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 267,
        "question": "The _____ class is a specialization of a more general template class",
        "answer": "A. String",
        "options": [
            "A. String",
            "B. Integer",
            "C. Digit",
            "D. Math"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 268,
        "question": "What if static members are declared inside template classes?",
        "answer": "B. All instances will have their own static variable",
        "options": [
            "A. All instances will share the static variable",
            "B. All instances will have their own static variable",
            "C. All the instances will ignore the static variable",
            "D. Program gives compile time error"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 269,
        "question": "If template class is defined, is it necessary to use different types of data for each call?",
        "answer": "A. No, not necessary",
        "options": [
            "A. No, not necessary",
            "B. No, but at least two types must be there",
            "C. Yes, to make proper use of template",
            "D. Yes, for code efficiency"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 270,
        "question": "Template classes must have at least one static member:",
        "answer": "B. False",
        "options": [
            "A. True",
            "B. False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 271,
        "question": "If there is a derived class in a program, how many classes must be in that program?",
        "answer": "B. 2",
        "options": [
            "A. 1",
            "B. 2",
            "C. 3",
            "D. 4"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 272,
        "question": "If base class is an abstract class then the derived class",
        "answer": "B. Must become another abstract class or define",
        "options": [
            "A. Must define",
            "B. Must become another abstract class or define",
            "C. Must become parent class for",
            "D. Must implement 2 definitions of"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 273,
        "question": "Deriving a class in such a way that the base class members are not available for further inheritance is known as",
        "answer": "D. Private inheritance",
        "options": [
            "A. Public inheritance",
            "B. Protected inheritance",
            "C. Protected or private inheritance",
            "D. Private inheritance"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 274,
        "question": "Which among the following is the main characteristic of class?",
        "answer": "B. Encapsulation",
        "options": [
            "A. Inheritance",
            "B. Encapsulation",
            "C. Polymorphism",
            "D. Object creation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 275,
        "question": "To group all the brands of cars, what should be used?",
        "answer": "A. Class",
        "options": [
            "A. Class",
            "B. Structure",
            "C. Function",
            "D. Object"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 276,
        "question": "Which among the following is an advantage of using classes over structures of C?",
        "answer": "C. Functions can also be encapsulated",
        "options": [
            "A. Functions are restricted",
            "B. Functions can't be defined",
            "C. Functions can also be encapsulated",
            "D. Functions can have more security"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 277,
        "question": "Why do we use user defined classes?",
        "answer": "B. To model real world objects",
        "options": [
            "A. To design a user intended code",
            "B. To model real world objects",
            "C. To design the interfaces",
            "D. To model the functions"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 278,
        "question": "Each class can inherit the base class",
        "answer": "A. Independently using any inheritance",
        "options": [
            "A. Independently using any inheritance",
            "B. Independently with private inheritance only",
            "C. With same type of inheritance",
            "D. With each class using different inheritance only"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 279,
        "question": "Which class uses hierarchical inheritance in following code? class A { int a; } class B : class A { int b; } class C : class A { int c; } class D : class A { int d; }",
        "answer": "D. Class D, A, B, C",
        "options": [
            "A. Class A, B, C",
            "B. Class B, C, D",
            "C. Class A, B",
            "D. Class D, A, B, C"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 280,
        "question": "If one class has derived the base class privately then another class can't derive the base class publicly",
        "answer": "B. False",
        "options": [
            "A. True",
            "B. False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 281,
        "question": "If a const object calls a non-const member function then",
        "answer": "B. Compile time error may get produced",
        "options": [
            "A. Run time error may get produced",
            "B. Compile time error may get produced",
            "C. Either compile time or run time error is produced",
            "D. The program can't be compiled"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 282,
        "question": "Can a constructor function be constant?",
        "answer": "D. No, never",
        "options": [
            "A. Yes, always",
            "B. Yes, only if permissions are given",
            "C. No, because objects are not involved",
            "D. No, never"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 283,
        "question": "A function can have both the const and non-const version in the same program.",
        "answer": "A. True",
        "options": [
            "A. True",
            "B. False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 284,
        "question": "Functions which differ in const-ness are considered",
        "answer": "B. To have different signature",
        "options": [
            "A. To have same signature",
            "B. To have different signature",
            "C. To produce runtime error",
            "D. To produce compile time error"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 285,
        "question": "Which is the universal exception handler class?",
        "answer": "D. Exceptions",
        "options": [
            "A. Object",
            "B. Math",
            "C. Errors",
            "D. Exceptions"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 286,
        "question": "Which are the two blocks that are used to check error and handle the error?",
        "answer": "A. Try and catch",
        "options": [
            "A. Try and catch",
            "B. Trying and catching",
            "C. Do and while",
            "D. TryDo and Check"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 287,
        "question": "How many catch blocks can a single try block have?",
        "answer": "D. As many as required",
        "options": [
            "A. Only 1",
            "B. Only 2",
            "C. Maximum 127",
            "D. As many as required"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 288,
        "question": "To catch the exceptions,",
        "answer": "A. An object must be created to catch the exception",
        "options": [
            "A. An object must be created to catch the exception",
            "B. An array should be created to catch all the exceptions",
            "C. A variable should be created to catch the exception",
            "D. A string has to be created to store the exception"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 289,
        "question": "Which symbol should be used to separate the type of exception handler classes in a single catch block?",
        "answer": "B. |",
        "options": [
            "A. ?",
            "B. |",
            "C. &",
            "D. !"
        ]
    },
    
    {
        "numb": 290,
        "question": "Why do we use finally block?",
        "answer": "D. To execute a code with each and every run of program",
        "options": [
            "A. To execute the block if exception occurred",
            "B. To execute a code when exception is not occurred",
            "C. To execute a code whenever required",
            "D. To execute a code with each and every run of program"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 291,
        "question": "Which among the following is a wrong call to the function void test(int x, int y=0, int z=0)?",
        "answer": "C. test()",
        "options": [
            "A. test(5, 6, 7)",
            "B. test(5)",
            "C. test()",
            "D. test(5, 6)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 292,
        "question": "Which among the following is false for default arguments?",
        "answer": "D. Those are allowed with pointer and reference to function declaration",
        "options": [
            "A. Those are not allowed with a declaration of pointer to functions",
            "B. Those are not allowed with the reference to functions",
            "C. Those are not allowed with the typedef declarations",
            "D. Those are allowed with pointer and reference to function declaration"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 293,
        "question": "The default arguments get bound during declaration",
        "answer": "D. But are executed during function call",
        "options": [
            "A. And are never executed",
            "B. And are executed simultaneously",
            "C. But are executed only if priority is given",
            "D. But are executed during function call"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 294,
        "question": "Which property is shown most when upcasting is used?",
        "answer": "C. Complex code simple syntax",
        "options": [
            "A. Code reusability",
            "B. Code efficiency",
            "C. Complex code simple syntax",
            "D. Encapsulation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 295,
        "question": "Upcasting and downcasting objects are the same as casting primitive types.",
        "answer": "B. False",
        "options": [
            "A. True",
            "B. False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 296,
        "question": "If class C inherits class B and class B inherits class A",
        "answer": "C. Class C object can be upcasted to object of either class A or B",
        "options": [
            "A. Class C object can be upcasted to object of class B only",
            "B. Class C object can be upcasted to object of class A only",
            "C. Class C object can be upcasted to object of either class A or B",
            "D. Class C object can't be upcasted"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 297,
        "question": "Which concept is needed because of implicit type casting use?",
        "answer": "B. Dynamic binding",
        "options": [
            "A. Static binding",
            "B. Dynamic binding",
            "C. Compile time binding",
            "D. Source code binding"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 298,
        "question": "What does function length do in String class?",
        "answer": "B. Returns length of string excluding null character",
        "options": [
            "A. Returns length of string including null character",
            "B. Returns length of string excluding null character",
            "C. Returns length of substring",
            "D. Returns size of string in bytes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 299,
        "question": "Which header file is required to use file I/O operations?",
        "answer": "C. <fstream>",
        "options": [
            "A. <ifstream>",
            "B. <ostream>",
            "C. <fstream>",
            "D. <iostream>"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 300,
        "question": "Which of the following is not used to seek file pointer?",
        "answer": "B. ios::end",
        "options": [
            "A. ios::set",
            "B. ios::end",
            "C. ios::cur",
            "D. ios::beg"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 301,
        "question": "Which of the following user-defined header file extension is used in C++?",
        "answer": "C. h",
        "options": [
            "A. hg",
            "B. cpp",
            "C. h",
            "D. hf"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 302,
        "question": "Which of the following is a correct identifier in C++?",
        "answer": "C. VAR_1234",
        "options": [
            "A. VAR 1234",
            "B. Svar name",
            "C. VAR_1234",
            "D. 7var_name"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 303,
        "question": "What happens if the following C++ statement is compiled and executed? int ptr = NULL; delete ptr;",
        "answer": "B. The program is compiled and executed successfully",
        "options": [
            "A. The program is not semantically correct",
            "B. The program is compiled and executed successfully",
            "C. The program gives a compile-time error",
            "D. The program compiles successfully but throws an error during run-time"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 304,
        "question": "What is the difference between delete and delete[] in C++?",
        "answer": "A. delete is syntactically correct but delete() is wrong",
        "options": [
            "A. delete is syntactically correct but delete() is wrong",
            "B. delete frees memory for a single object, delete[] for an array",
            "C. delete[] is used for pointers, delete for references",
            "D. delete is for dynamic memory, delete[] for static memory"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 305,
        "question": "What is OOP?",
        "answer": "A. Object Oriented Programming",
        "options": [
            "A. Object Oriented Programming",
            "B. Object Oriented Protocol",
            "C. Object Oriented Procedure",
            "D. Object Oriented Practice"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 306,
        "question": "Who invented OOP?",
        "answer": "C. Alan Kay",
        "options": [
            "A. Andrea Ferro",
            "B. Adele Goldberg",
            "C. Alan Kay",
            "D. Dennis Ritchie"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 307,
        "question": "Which was the first purely object-oriented programming language developed?",
        "answer": "B. SmallTalk",
        "options": [
            "A. Kotlin",
            "B. SmallTalk",
            "C. Java",
            "D. C++"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 308,
        "question": "What is the syntax of inheritance in C++?",
        "answer": "A. class derived_classname: access base_classname { /define class body/ }",
        "options": [
            "A. class derived_classname: access base_classname { /define class body/ }",
            "B. class base_classname access derived_classname { /define class body/ }",
            "C. class derived_classname: base_classname { /define class body/ }",
            "D. class base_classname: derived_classname { /define class body/ }"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 309,
        "question": "Which feature of OOP indicates code reusability?",
        "answer": "D. Inheritance",
        "options": [
            "A. Abstraction",
            "B. Polymorphism",
            "C. Encapsulation",
            "D. Inheritance"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 310,
        "question": "How many types of access specifiers are provided in OOP (C++)?",
        "answer": "B. 3",
        "options": [
            "A. 4",
            "B. 3",
            "C. 2",
            "D. 1"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 311,
        "question": "Which among the following is correct for the class defined below?\n\nclass student\n{\nint marks;\n\npublic:\nstudent() {}\nstudent(int x)\n{ marks=x; }\n};\n\nint main()\n{\nstudent s1(100);\nstudent s2();\nstudent s3=100;\nreturn 0;\n}\n\n",
        "answer": "D. Program runs and all objects are created",
        "options": [
            "A. Program will give compile-time error",
            "B. Object s3, syntax error",
            "C. Only object s1 and s2 will be created",
            "D. Program runs and all objects are created"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 312,
        "question": "Which among the following represents correct constructor?",
        "answer": "B. classname()",
        "options": [
            "A. -classname()",
            "B. classname()",
            "C. (classname",
            "D. -classname()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 313,
        "question": "What happens when an object is passed by reference?",
        "answer": "C. Destructor is not called",
        "options": [
            "A. Destructor is called at end of function",
            "B. Destructor is called when called explicitly",
            "C. Destructor is not called",
            "D. Destructor is called when function is out of scope"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 314,
        "question": "Which feature of OOP reduces the use of nested classes?",
        "answer": "A. Inheritance",
        "options": [
            "A. Inheritance",
            "B. Binding",
            "C. Abstraction",
            "D. Encapsulation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 315,
        "question": "Which operator can be used to free the memory allocated for an object in C++?",
        "answer": "D. delete",
        "options": [
            "A. Unallocate",
            "B. Free()",
            "C. Collect",
            "D. delete"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 316,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a property of an object?",
        "answer": "B. Names",
        "options": [
            "A. Properties",
            "B. Names",
            "C. Identity",
            "D. Attributes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 317,
        "question": "Which among the following best describes Inheritance?",
        "answer": "A. Using the data and functions into derived segment",
        "options": [
            "A. Using the data and functions into derived segment",
            "B. Using already defined functions in a programming language",
            "C. Using the code already written once",
            "D. Copying the code already written"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 318,
        "question": "What is a class in C++?",
        "answer": "D. A structure",
        "options": [
            "A. A function",
            "B. A variable",
            "C. A data type",
            "D. A structure"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 319,
        "question": "What is encapsulation in OOP?",
        "answer": "A. Combining data members and member functions into a single unit",
        "options": [
            "A. Combining data members and member functions into a single unit",
            "B. Hiding implementation details of an object from the user",
            "C. Creating a new class from an existing class",
            "D. Creating a new object from an existing object"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 320,
        "question": "What is an abstract data type in OOP?",
        "answer": "B. A data type that cannot be instantiated",
        "options": [
            "A. A data type that can be instantiated",
            "B. A data type that cannot be instantiated",
            "C. A data type that can be passed by value",
            "D. A data type that can be passed by reference"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 321,
        "question": "Encapsulation and abstraction differ as",
        "answer": "B. Binding and Hiding respectively",
        "options": [
            "A. Hiding and hiding respectively",
            "B. Binding and Hiding respectively",
            "C. Hiding and Binding respectively",
            "D. Can be used any way"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 322,
        "question": "Which feature of OOP is exhibited by function overriding?",
        "answer": "A. Polymorphism",
        "options": [
            "A. Polymorphism",
            "B. Encapsulation",
            "C. Abstraction",
            "D. Inheritance"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 323,
        "question": "How to access the private member function of a class?",
        "answer": "D. Using address of member function",
        "options": [
            "A. Using class address",
            "B. Using object of class",
            "C. Using object pointer",
            "D. Using address of member function"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 324,
        "question": "Which keyword should be used to declare static variables?",
        "answer": "C. static",
        "options": [
            "A. const",
            "B. common",
            "C. static",
            "D. stat"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 325,
        "question": "Which class/set of classes can illustrate polymorphism in the following C++ code?\n\nabstract class student\n{\npublic:\nint marks;\ncalc_grade()\n{\n}\n};\n\nclass topper : public student\n{\npublic:\ncalc_grade()\n{\nreturn 10;\n}\n};\n\nclass average : public student\n{\npublic:\ncalc_grade()\n{\nreturn 20;\n}\n};\n\nclass failed : public student\n{\npublic:\ncalc_grade()\n{\nreturn 0;\n}\n};",
        "answer": "D. All class student, topper, and average together can show polymorphism",
        "options": [
            "A. Only class student and topper together can show polymorphism",
            "B. Only class student can show polymorphism",
            "C. Class failed should also inherit class student for this code to work for polymorphism",
            "D. All class student, topper, and average together can show polymorphism"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 326,
        "question": "If data members are private, what can we do to access them from the class object?",
        "answer": "B. Create public member functions to access those data members",
        "options": [
            "A. Private data members can never be accessed from outside the class",
            "B. Create public member functions to access those data members",
            "C. Create private member functions to access those data members",
            "D. Create protected member functions to access those data members"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 327,
        "question": "Which among the following is not a necessary condition for constructors?",
        "answer": "C. It must contain a definition body",
        "options": [
            "A. Its name must be same as that of class",
            "B. It must not have any return type",
            "C. It must contain a definition body",
            "D. It can contain arguments"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 328,
        "question": "Which feature in OOP is used to allocate additional functions to a predefined operator in any language?",
        "answer": "C. Operator Overloading",
        "options": [
            "A. Function Overloading",
            "B. Function Overriding",
            "C. Operator Overloading",
            "D. Operator Overriding"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 329,
        "question": "Which among the following can restrict class members to be inherited?",
        "answer": "A. Private",
        "options": [
            "A. Private",
            "B. Protected",
            "C. Public",
            "D. All three"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 330,
        "question": "Data members in classes",
        "answer": "B. Can be initialized only with help of constructors",
        "options": [
            "A. Can be initialized with declaration in classes",
            "B. Can be initialized only with help of constructors",
            "C. Can be initialized either in declaration or by constructor",
            "D. Can't be initialized"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 331,
        "question": "How many data members can a class contain?",
        "answer": "D. As many as required",
        "options": [
            "A. 27",
            "B. 255",
            "C. 1024",
            "D. As many as required"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 332,
        "question": "What is the output of the following code?\n\nint n=10;\nclass A {\nprivate:\nint n;\npublic:\nint m;\nA() { n=100; m=50; }\nvoid disp() { cout<<n<<m<<::n; }\n};",
        "answer": "D. 1005010",
        "options": [
            "A. 1050100",
            "B. 1005010",
            "C. 105010",
            "D. 1005010"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 333,
        "question": "A class can have self-referential data members.",
        "answer": "B. False",
        "options": [
            "A. True",
            "B. False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 334,
        "question": "Which data members can be inherited but are private to a class?",
        "answer": "B. Protected",
        "options": [
            "A. Private",
            "B. Protected",
            "C. Public",
            "D. Privately inherited"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 335,
        "question": "The arguments passed to member functions by reference are considered as data members of class.",
        "answer": "B. False",
        "options": [
            "A. True",
            "B. False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 336,
        "question": "Which among the following is not allowed for data member declaration?",
        "answer": "C. abstract a;",
        "options": [
            "A. int a;",
            "B. static int a;",
            "C. abstract a;",
            "D. Boolean a;"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 337,
        "question": "What are local classes?",
        "answer": "B. Classes declared inside a function",
        "options": [
            "A. Classes declared inside a package",
            "B. Classes declared inside a function",
            "C. Classes declared inside a class",
            "D. Classes declared inside a structure"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 338,
        "question": "All member functions of a local class must be:",
        "answer": "C. Defined inside the class body",
        "options": [
            "A. Defined outside the class body",
            "B. Defined outside the function definition",
            "C. Defined inside the class body",
            "D. Defined at the start of the program"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 339,
        "question": "Can static variables be declared inside a local class?",
        "answer": "D. No, not possible anyway",
        "options": [
            "A. Yes, with public access specifier",
            "B. Yes, anywhere as required",
            "C. No, not possible in private access specifier",
            "D. No, not possible anyway"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 340,
        "question": "How many categories are nested classes divided into?",
        "answer": "A. 2",
        "options": [
            "A. 2",
            "B. 3",
            "C. 4",
            "D. 5"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 341,
        "question": "Static nested classes don't have access to enclosing class's:",
        "answer": "D. Any other members",
        "options": [
            "A. Private members",
            "B. Protected members",
            "C. Public members",
            "D. Any other members"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 342,
        "question": "Use of nested class:",
        "answer": "A. Increases encapsulation",
        "options": [
            "A. Increases encapsulation",
            "B. Decreases encapsulation",
            "C. Slightly decreases encapsulation",
            "D. Doesn't affect encapsulation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 343,
        "question": "Which among the following is the correct advantage/disadvantage of nested classes?",
        "answer": "C. Makes the code efficient and readable",
        "options": [
            "A. Makes the code more complex",
            "B. Makes the code unreadable",
            "C. Makes the code efficient and readable",
            "D. Makes the code multithreaded"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 344,
        "question": "Instance of inner class can exist only:",
        "answer": "A. Within the enclosing class",
        "options": [
            "A. Within the enclosing class",
            "B. Outside the enclosing class",
            "C. Private to the enclosing class",
            "D. Public to the enclosing class"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 345,
        "question": "Which among the following is true?",
        "answer": "A. First the constructor of parent classes are called in sequence of inheritance",
        "options": [
            "A. First the constructor of parent classes are called in sequence of inheritance",
            "B. First the constructor of child classes are called in sequence of inheritance",
            "C. First constructor called is of the object being created",
            "D. Constructors are called randomly"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 346,
        "question": "The destructors:",
        "answer": "B. Can't have any argument",
        "options": [
            "A. Can have maximum one argument",
            "B. Can't have any argument",
            "C. Can have more than one argument",
            "D. Can't have more than three arguments"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 347,
        "question": "If a class has 4 constructors then it must have 4 destructors also.",
        "answer": "B. False",
        "options": [
            "A. True",
            "B. False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 348,
        "question": "Which among the following is true for destructors?",
        "answer": "C. Destructors can't be overloaded",
        "options": [
            "A. Destructors can be overloaded",
            "B. Destructors can be defined more than once",
            "C. Destructors can't be overloaded",
            "D. Destructors are overloaded in derived classes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 349,
        "question": "Which among the following describes a destructor?",
        "answer": "A. A special function that is called to free the resources acquired by the object",
        "options": [
            "A. A special function that is called to free the resources acquired by the object",
            "B. A special function that is called to delete the class",
            "C. A special function that is called anytime to delete an object",
            "D. A special function that is called to delete all the objects of class"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 350,
        "question": "Destructors don't accept parameters.",
        "answer": "A. True",
        "options": [
            "A. True",
            "B. False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 351,
        "question": "Which class destructor will be called first, when the following code goes out of scope?\n\nclass A {\npublic:\n~A() {}\n};\nclass B : public A {\npublic:\n~B() {}\n};\nclass C : public B {\npublic:\n~C() {}\n};\nint main() {\n    C c;\n    return 0;\n}",
        "answer": "C. ~C()",
        "options": [
            "A. ~A()",
            "B. ~B()",
            "C. ~C()",
            "D. ~B() and ~C()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 352,
        "question": "What happens when an object is passed by reference?",
        "answer": "A. Destructor is not called",
        "options": [
            "A. Destructor is not called",
            "B. Destructor is called at the end of function",
            "C. Destructor is called when function is out of scope",
            "D. Destructor is called when called explicitly"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 353,
        "question": "What is the term used to indicate the variables and constants of a class?",
        "answer": "A. Data members",
        "options": [
            "A. Data members",
            "B. Variables of class",
            "C. Data characters",
            "D. Constants"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 354,
        "question": "Which among the following is true for data members?",
        "answer": "D. Static data members are defined outside class, not in constructor",
        "options": [
            "A. Private data members can be initialized with declaration in class",
            "B. Static members are initialized in constructors",
            "C. Protected data members can be initialized in class directly",
            "D. Static data members are defined outside class, not in constructor"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 355,
        "question": "Constructor function is not called when an object is passed to a function. Will its destructor be called when its copy is destroyed?",
        "answer": "B. Yes, must be called",
        "options": [
            "A. Yes, depending on code",
            "B. Yes, must be called",
            "C. No, since no constructor was called",
            "D. No, since the same object gets used"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 356,
        "question": "How to overcome the problem arising due to destruction of temporary object?",
        "answer": "D. Overloading assignment operator and defining copy constructor",
        "options": [
            "A. Overloading insertion operator",
            "B. Overriding functions can be used",
            "C. Overloading parenthesis or returning object",
            "D. Overloading assignment operator and defining copy constructor"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 357,
        "question": "What is reference to an object?",
        "answer": "B. It is the address of where the variables and methods of object are stored",
        "options": [
            "A. It is the address of an object",
            "B. It is the address of where the variables and methods of object are stored",
            "C. It is a pointer having address of an object",
            "D. It is the address of only variables and not the methods of an object"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 358,
        "question": "Which among the following is true?",
        "answer": "C. Object referencing points to the same address, if assigned by variables",
        "options": [
            "A. Object referencing refers to methods' address",
            "B. Object referencing refers to variable of object",
            "C. Object referencing points to the same address, if assigned by variables",
            "D. Object referencing is used to point methods"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 359,
        "question": "What does memory allocation for objects mean?",
        "answer": "A. Actual creation and memory allocation for object members",
        "options": [
            "A. Actual creation and memory allocation for object members",
            "B. Creation of member functions",
            "C. Creation of data members for a class",
            "D. Actual creation and data declaration for object members"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 360,
        "question": "Which among the following keyword can be used to free the allocated memory for an object?",
        "answer": "C. either delete or free",
        "options": [
            "A. delete",
            "B. free",
            "C. either delete or free",
            "D. only delete"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 361,
        "question": "Which function is called whenever an object goes out of scope?",
        "answer": "A. Destructor function",
        "options": [
            "A. Destructor function",
            "B. Constructor function",
            "C. Delete function",
            "D. Free function"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 362,
        "question": "What is an array of objects?",
        "answer": "A. An array of instances of class represented by a single name",
        "options": [
            "A. An array of instances of class represented by a single name",
            "B. An array of instances of class represented by more than one name",
            "C. An array of instances which have more than two instances",
            "D. An array of instances which have different types"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 363,
        "question": "What is the type of elements of array of objects?",
        "answer": "A. Class",
        "options": [
            "A. Class",
            "B. Void",
            "C. String",
            "D. Null"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 364,
        "question": "When are the array of objects without any initialization useful?",
        "answer": "A. When object data is not required just after the declaration",
        "options": [
            "A. When object data is not required just after the declaration",
            "B. When initialization of object data is to be made by the compiler",
            "C. When object data doesn't matter in the program",
            "D. When the object should contain garbage data"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 365,
        "question": "The Object array is created in",
        "answer": "(a) Heap memory",
        "options": [
            "(a) Heap memory",
            "(b) Stack memory",
            "(c) HDD",
            "(d) ROM"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 366,
        "question": "Can we have a two-dimensional object array?",
        "answer": "(a) Yes, always",
        "options": [
            "(a) Yes, always",
            "(b) Yes, only if primitive type array",
            "(c) No, since two indices are impossible",
            "(d) No, never"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 367,
        "question": "What is a function object?",
        "answer": "(a) An object with a single function",
        "options": [
            "(a) An object with a single function",
            "(b) An object with only functions",
            "(c) An object with more than one function",
            "(d) An object with no functions"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 368,
        "question": "Which object can be used to contain other objects?",
        "answer": "(c) Container object",
        "options": [
            "(a) First class object",
            "(b) Derived class object",
            "(c) Container object",
            "(d) Enclosure object"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 369,
        "question": "A factory object is used",
        "answer": "(b) To create new function",
        "options": [
            "(a) To create new classes",
            "(b) To create new function",
            "(c) To create new data members",
            "(d) To create new objects"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 370,
        "question": "Object cout and cin",
        "answer": "(a) Can be used directly with << and >> symbols respectively",
        "options": [
            "(a) Can be used directly with << and >> symbols respectively",
            "(b) Can be used directly with >> and << symbols respectively",
            "(c) Must be used as a function which accepts 2 arguments",
            "(d) Must be used as a function which accepts 3 arguments"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 371,
        "question": "Objects type",
        "answer": "(b) Can't be changed in runtime",
        "options": [
            "(a) Can be changed in runtime",
            "(b) Can't be changed in runtime",
            "(c) Can be changed in compile time",
            "(d) May or may not get changed"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 372,
        "question": "Which among the following is not a use of object?",
        "answer": "(a) Defining a member function",
        "options": [
            "(a) Defining a member function",
            "(b) Accessing data members",
            "(c) Creating instance of a class",
            "(d) Using class members"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 373,
        "question": "Which object can be used to access the standard input?",
        "answer": "(b) cin",
        "options": [
            "(a) System.inner",
            "(b) cin",
            "(c) System stdin",
            "(d) console.input"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 374,
        "question": "If a class is inheriting another abstract class having abstract method, then",
        "answer": "(a) Either implementation of method or making class abstract is mandatory",
        "options": [
            "(a) Either implementation of method or making class abstract is mandatory",
            "(b) Implementation of the method in derived class is mandatory",
            "(c) Making the derived class also abstract is mandatory",
            "(d) It's not mandatory to implement the abstract method of parent class"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 375,
        "question": "How many abstract classes can a single program contain?",
        "answer": "(d) As many as required",
        "options": [
            "(a) At most 1",
            "(b) At least 1",
            "(c) At most 127",
            "(d) As many as required"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 376,
        "question": "Is it necessary that all the abstract methods must be defined from an abstract class?",
        "answer": "(b) Yes, always",
        "options": [
            "(a) Yes depending on code",
            "(b) Yes, always",
            "(c) No, never",
            "(d) If function is not used, no definition is required"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 377,
        "question": "A template class can have",
        "answer": "(a) More than one generic data type",
        "options": [
            "(a) More than one generic data type",
            "(b) Only one generic data type",
            "(c) At most two data types",
            "(d) Only generic type of integers and not characters"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 378,
        "question": "Which among the following is a feature of class?",
        "answer": "(a) Object orientation",
        "options": [
            "(a) Object orientation",
            "(b) Procedure orientation",
            "(c) Both object and procedure orientation",
            "(d) Neither object nor procedure orientation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 379,
        "question": "What is the use of inbuilt classes?",
        "answer": "(c) Provide predefined data and functions",
        "options": [
            "(a) Provide predefined data",
            "(b) Provide predefined functions",
            "(c) Provide predefined data and functions",
            "(d) Provide predeclared data to be overridden"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 380,
        "question": "Why do classes use accessor methods?",
        "answer": "(d) To make private data accessible to the client",
        "options": [
            "(a) To make public data accessible to client",
            "(b) To make public data private to client",
            "(c) To make private data public for the whole program",
            "(d) To make private data accessible to the client"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 381,
        "question": "Why do classes use mutator methods?",
        "answer": "(b) Allows client to modify/write the private members",
        "options": [
            "(a) Allows client to modify the program",
            "(b) Allows client to modify/write the private members",
            "(c) Allows servers to access all the private data",
            "(d) Allows servers to access only protected members"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 382,
        "question": "Which among the following is best to define hierarchical inheritance?",
        "answer": "(a) More than one classes being derived from one class",
        "options": [
            "(a) More than one classes being derived from one class",
            "(b) More than 2 classes being derived from single base class",
            "(c) At most 2 classes being derived from single base class",
            "(d) At most 1 class derived from another class"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 383,
        "question": "How many classes must there be to implement hierarchical inheritance?",
        "answer": "(b) At least 3",
        "options": [
            "(a) Exactly 3",
            "(b) At least 3",
            "(c) At most 3",
            "(d) At least 1"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 384,
        "question": "Base class",
        "answer": "(a) Can be made abstract",
        "options": [
            "(a) Can be made abstract",
            "(b) Can't be made abstract",
            "(c) Must be abstract",
            "(d) If made abstract, compile-time error"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 385,
        "question": "Hierarchical inheritance can be a subset of",
        "answer": "(a) Hybrid inheritance",
        "options": [
            "(a) Hybrid inheritance",
            "(b) Multiple inheritance",
            "(c) Single level inheritance",
            "(d) Multilevel inheritance"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 386,
        "question": "Which class constructor is called first when an object of derived class is created?",
        "answer": "(a) Base class constructor",
        "options": [
            "(a) Base class constructor",
            "(b) Derived class constructor",
            "(c) Firstly created derived class constructor",
            "(d) Last created derived class constructor"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 387,
        "question": "What does memory allocation for objects mean?",
        "answer": "(a) Actual creation and memory allocation for object members",
        "options": [
            "(a) Actual creation and memory allocation for object members",
            "(b) Creation of member functions",
            "(c) Creation of data members for a class",
            "(d) Actual creation and data declaration for object members"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 388,
        "question": "Which objects can call the const functions?",
        "answer": "(c) Both const and non-const objects",
        "options": [
            "(a) Only const objects",
            "(b) Only non-const objects",
            "(c) Both const and non-const objects",
            "(d) Neither const nor non-const objects"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 389,
        "question": "Non-const functions",
        "answer": "(a) Can be called only from non-const object",
        "options": [
            "(a) Can be called only from non-const object",
            "(b) Can be called only from const object",
            "(c) Can be called both by const and non-const object",
            "(d) Can't be called with object"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 390,
        "question": "If const version of a function when overloading is used, the function",
        "answer": "(d) Returns const reference",
        "options": [
            "(a) Returns reference to object",
            "(b) Returns volatile reference",
            "(c) Returns mutable reference",
            "(d) Returns const reference"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 391,
        "question": "What is an exception?",
        "answer": "(b) Problem arising during runtime",
        "options": [
            "(a) Problem arising during compile time",
            "(b) Problem arising during runtime",
            "(c) Problem in syntax",
            "(d) Problem in IDE"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 392,
        "question": "Why do we need to handle exceptions?",
        "answer": "(a) To prevent abnormal termination of program",
        "options": [
            "(a) To prevent abnormal termination of program",
            "(b) To encourage exception prone program",
            "(c) To avoid syntax errors",
            "(d) To save memory"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 393,
        "question": "Multiple catch blocks",
        "answer": "(b) Can be combined into a single catch block",
        "options": [
            "(a) Are mandatory for each try block",
            "(b) Can be combined into a single catch block",
            "(c) Are not possible for a try block",
            "(d) Can never be associated with a single try block"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 394,
        "question": "Which is the correct condition for the default arguments?",
        "answer": "(a) Those must be declared as last arguments in argument list",
        "options": [
            "(a) Those must be declared as last arguments in argument list",
            "(b) Those must be declared first in the argument list",
            "(c) Those can be defined anywhere in the argument list",
            "(d) Those are declared inside the function definition"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 395,
        "question": "Which among the following function can be called without arguments?",
        "answer": "(c) void add(int x=0, int y=0)",
        "options": [
            "(a) void add(int x, int y=0)",
            "(b) void add(int=0)",
            "(c) void add(int x=0, int y=0)",
            "(d) void add(char c)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 396,
        "question": "What is upcasting?",
        "answer": "(a) Casting subtype to supertype",
        "options": [
            "(a) Casting subtype to supertype",
            "(b) Casting supertype to subtype",
            "(c) Casting subtype to supertype and vice versa",
            "(d) Casting any type to any other type"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 397,
        "question": "Which among the following is safe?",
        "answer": "(a) Upcasting",
        "options": [
            "(a) Upcasting",
            "(b) Downcasting",
            "(c) Both upcasting and downcasting",
            "(d) If upcasting is safe then downcasting is not, and vice versa"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 398,
        "question": "Which among the following is true?",
        "answer": "(d) Upcasting is possible for any type of inheritance",
        "options": [
            "(a) Upcasting is possible only for single level inheritance",
            "(b) Upcasting is possible only for multilevel inheritance",
            "(c) Upcasting is possible only for multiple inheritance",
            "(d) Upcasting is possible for any type of inheritance"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 399,
        "question": "Which of the following statements are correct?",
        "answer": "(b) It is possible to combine two or more file opening modes in open() method",
        "options": [
            "(a) It is not possible to combine two or more file opening modes in open() method.",
            "(b) It is possible to combine two or more file opening modes in open() method.",
            "(c) ios::in and ios::out are input and output file opening modes, respectively.",
            "(d) ios::in and ios::out are output and input file opening modes, respectively."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 400,
        "question": "How to declare an object of class String?",
        "answer": "(a) String object_Name = value;",
        "options": [
            "(a) String object_Name = value;",
            "(b) String object_name = new",
            "(c) String object_name = new value;",
            "(d) String object_name = value new;"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 401,
        "question": "What is the use of ios::trunc mode?",
        "answer": "(d) To truncate an existing file to zero",
        "options": [
            "(a) To open a file in input mode",
            "(b) To open a file in output mode",
            "(c) To truncate an existing file to half",
            "(d) To truncate an existing file to zero"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 402,
        "question": "By default, all the files in C++ are opened in",
        "answer": "(a) Text mode",
        "options": [
            "(a) Text",
            "(b) Binary",
            "(c) ISCII",
            "(d) VTC"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 403,
        "question": "String class has a concat() function that is used to",
        "answer": "(c) Append one string at the end of another string",
        "options": [
            "(a) Replace old string by new string",
            "(b) Add two strings",
            "(c) Append one string at the end of another string",
            "(d) Remove a string from the end of one string"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 404,
        "question": "In object-oriented programming the program is divided into",
        "answer": "(a) Class",
        "options": [
            "(a) Class",
            "(b) Object",
            "(c) Function",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 405,
        "question": "Which one is the Object Oriented Programming language?",
        "answer": "(c) C++",
        "options": [
            "(a) Cobol",
            "(b) C",
            "(c) C++",
            "(d) Both C & C++"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 406,
        "question": "The wrapping up of data and functions into a single unit is called",
        "answer": "(b) Encapsulation",
        "options": [
            "(a) Inheritance",
            "(b) Encapsulation",
            "(c) Data hiding",
            "(d) Polymorphism"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 407,
        "question": "The process by which objects of one class acquire the properties of objects of another class is called",
        "answer": "(b) Inheritance",
        "options": [
            "(a) Abstraction",
            "(b) Inheritance",
            "(c) Encapsulation",
            "(d) Polymorphism"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 408,
        "question": "In OOP which concept provides the idea of reusability?",
        "answer": "(a) Inheritance",
        "options": [
            "(a) Inheritance",
            "(b) Encapsulation",
            "(c) Data hiding",
            "(d) Polymorphism"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 409,
        "question": "The process of making an operator exhibit different behaviours in different instances is called",
        "answer": "(b) Operator overloading",
        "options": [
            "(a) Function overloading",
            "(b) Operator overloading",
            "(c) Inheritance",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 410,
        "question": "The process of making a function exhibit different behaviours in different instances is called",
        "answer": "(a) Function overloading",
        "options": [
            "(a) Function overloading",
            "(b) Operator overloading",
            "(c) Inheritance",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 411,
        "question": "Objects communicate with one another by using",
        "answer": "(a) Message passing",
        "options": [
            "(a) Message passing",
            "(b) Operator overloading",
            "(c) Inheritance",
            "(d) Both (a) & (b)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 412,
        "question": "Through ___ we can eliminate redundant code and extend the use of an existing class",
        "answer": "(a) Inheritance",
        "options": [
            "(a) Inheritance",
            "(b) Operator overloading",
            "(c) Encapsulation",
            "(d) Both (a) & (b)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 413,
        "question": "The principle of ___ helps the programmer build secure programs",
        "answer": "(b) Encapsulation",
        "options": [
            "(a) Operator overloading",
            "(b) Encapsulation",
            "(c) Data hiding",
            "(d) Polymorphism"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 414,
        "question": "What are the basic runtime entities in an object-oriented program?",
        "answer": "(a) Objects",
        "options": [
            "(a) Objects",
            "(b) Functions",
            "(c) Data",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 415,
        "question": "OOP follows ___ approach during program design.",
        "answer": "(b) Bottom-up",
        "options": [
            "(a) Top-down",
            "(b) Bottom-up",
            "(c) Both (a) and (b)",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 416,
        "question": "The technique of hiding internal details in an object is called",
        "answer": "(a) Encapsulation",
        "options": [
            "(a) Encapsulation",
            "(b) Functions",
            "(c) Abstraction",
            "(d) Inheritance"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 417,
        "question": "Classes are ___ data types.",
        "answer": "(b) User-defined",
        "options": [
            "(a) Derived",
            "(b) User-defined",
            "(c) Built-in",
            "(d) Both (a) & (c)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 418,
        "question": "___ provides an interface between the object's data and the program",
        "answer": "(b) Functions",
        "options": [
            "(a) Object",
            "(b) Functions",
            "(c) Class",
            "(d) Polymorphism"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 419,
        "question": "___ refers to the linking of a procedure call to the code to be executed in response to the call",
        "answer": "(c) Dynamic binding",
        "options": [
            "(a) Polymorphism",
            "(b) Functions",
            "(c) Dynamic binding",
            "(d) Message passing"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 420,
        "question": "A ___ for an object is a request for execution of a procedure.",
        "answer": "(d) Message passing",
        "options": [
            "(a) Object",
            "(b) Functions",
            "(c) Dynamic binding",
            "(d) Message passing"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 421,
        "question": "The << operator is known as",
        "answer": "(c) Insertion",
        "options": [
            "(a) Put to",
            "(b) Get from",
            "(c) Insertion",
            "(d) Both (a) & (c)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 422,
        "question": "The >> operator is known as",
        "answer": "(c) Extraction",
        "options": [
            "(a) Put to",
            "(b) Get from",
            "(c) Extraction",
            "(d) Both (b) & (c)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 423,
        "question": "___ contains function prototypes for the standard input and output functions",
        "answer": "(b) iostream.h",
        "options": [
            "(a) iomanip.h",
            "(b) iostream.h",
            "(c) stdlib.h",
            "(d) Both (a) & (c)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 424,
        "question": "In C++, the default return type for all functions is",
        "answer": "(a) Int",
        "options": [
            "(a) Int",
            "(b) Void",
            "(c) Float",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 425,
        "question": "The multiple use of input and output operators is called",
        "answer": "(c) Cascading",
        "options": [
            "(a) Polymorphism",
            "(b) Inheritance",
            "(c) Cascading",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 426,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a feature of OOPS?",
        "answer": "(d) None of these",
        "options": [
            "(a) Polymorphism",
            "(b) Inheritance",
            "(c) Dynamic binding",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 427,
        "question": "By default, the members of a C++ class are",
        "answer": "(a) Private",
        "options": [
            "(a) Private",
            "(b) Public",
            "(c) Protected",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 428,
        "question": "Which of the following functions must be present in all C++ programs?",
        "answer": "(c) main()",
        "options": [
            "(a) start()",
            "(b) system()",
            "(c) main()",
            "(d) program()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 429,
        "question": "Which one of the following is the correct operator to compare two values?",
        "answer": "(d) ==",
        "options": [
            "(a) =",
            "(b) ==",
            "(c) Equal",
            "(d) =="
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 430,
        "question": "C++ was originally developed by",
        "answer": "(c) Bjarne Stroustrup",
        "options": [
            "(a) Nicolas Wirth",
            "(b) Dennis Ritchie",
            "(c) Bjarne Stroustrup",
            "(d) Ken Thompson"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 431,
        "question": "Identify the unary operator",
        "answer": "(b) ++",
        "options": [
            "(a) +",
            "(b) ++",
            "(c) -",
            "(d) %"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 432,
        "question": "The ___ are used to check the relationship between two numeric operands or expressions.",
        "answer": "(b) Relational operators",
        "options": [
            "(a) Logical operators",
            "(b) Relational operators",
            "(c) Arithmetic operators",
            "(d) Bitwise operators"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 433,
        "question": "___ is a function that is expanded inline when it is invoked",
        "answer": "(c) Inline function",
        "options": [
            "(a) Library function",
            "(b) User-defined function",
            "(c) Inline function",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 434,
        "question": "The qualifier ___ tells the compiler that the function should not modify the argument.",
        "answer": "(a) Const",
        "options": [
            "(a) Const",
            "(b) Static",
            "(c) Constant",
            "(d) Inline"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 435,
        "question": "___ refers to the use of the same thing for different purposes.",
        "answer": "(b) Overloading",
        "options": [
            "(a) Function declaration",
            "(b) Overloading",
            "(c) Function calling",
            "(d) Prototyping"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 436,
        "question": "The functions declared inside the class are known as",
        "answer": "(c) Member functions",
        "options": [
            "(a) Data members",
            "(b) Library functions",
            "(c) Member functions",
            "(d) User-defined functions"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 437,
        "question": "Calling a member function by using its name from another member function of the same class is known as",
        "answer": "(c) Nesting of member function",
        "options": [
            "(a) Grouping of member function",
            "(b) Member function group",
            "(c) Nesting of member function",
            "(d) Nested group of member function"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 438,
        "question": "A ___ function can only be called by another function that is a member of its class.",
        "answer": "(b) Private member function",
        "options": [
            "(a) Member function",
            "(b) Private member function",
            "(c) Nested member function",
            "(d) Public member function"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 439,
        "question": "___ are normally used to maintain values common to the entire class.",
        "answer": "(b) Static variables",
        "options": [
            "(a) Dynamic variables",
            "(b) Static variables",
            "(c) Private variables",
            "(d) Public variables"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 440,
        "question": "A static variable is initialized to ___ when the first object of its class is created.",
        "answer": "(c) 0",
        "options": [
            "(a) 1",
            "(b) Null",
            "(c) 0",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 441,
        "question": "A function calling itself is known as",
        "answer": "(d) Recursion",
        "options": [
            "(a) Inline function",
            "(b) Static function",
            "(c) Friend function",
            "(d) Recursion"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 442,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a type of constructor?",
        "answer": "(b) Friend constructor",
        "options": [
            "(a) Copy constructor",
            "(b) Friend constructor",
            "(c) Default constructor",
            "(d) Parameterized constructor"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 443,
        "question": "Constructor is executed when",
        "answer": "(a) An object is created",
        "options": [
            "(a) An object is created",
            "(b) An object is used",
            "(c) A class is declared",
            "(d) An object goes out of scope"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 444,
        "question": "Which of the following is also known as an instance of a class?",
        "answer": "(b) Object",
        "options": [
            "(a) Friend functions",
            "(b) Object",
            "(c) Member functions",
            "(d) Member"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 445,
        "question": "A constructor that accepts parameters is called the default constructor.",
        "answer": "(c) No",
        "options": [
            "(a) One",
            "(b) Two",
            "(c) No",
            "(d) Three"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 446,
        "question": "Destructor has the same name as the constructor and it is preceded by",
        "answer": "(c) ~",
        "options": [
            "(a) +",
            "(b) -",
            "(c) ~",
            "(d) !"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 447,
        "question": "Which constructor function is designed to copy objects of the same class type?",
        "answer": "(d) Copy constructor",
        "options": [
            "(a) Create constructor",
            "(b) Object constructor",
            "(c) Dynamic constructor",
            "(d) Copy constructor"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 448,
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
        "answer": "(a) A constructor has the same name as the class in which it is present",
        "options": [
            "(a) A constructor has the same name as the class in which it is present",
            "(b) A constructor has a different name than the class in which it is present",
            "(c) A constructor always returns an integer",
            "(d) A constructor cannot be overloaded"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 449,
        "question": "A destructor takes ___ arguments.",
        "answer": "(d) No",
        "options": [
            "(a) One",
            "(b) Two",
            "(c) Three",
            "(d) No"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 450,
        "question": "Destructor calls are made in which order compared to the corresponding constructor calls?",
        "answer": "(a) Reverse order",
        "options": [
            "(a) Reverse order",
            "(b) Forward order",
            "(c) Depends on how the object is constructed",
            "(d) Depends on how many objects are constructed"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 451,
        "question": "Which allows you to create a derived class that inherits properties from more than one base class?",
        "answer": "(b) Multiple inheritance",
        "options": [
            "(a) Multilevel inheritance",
            "(b) Multiple inheritance",
            "(c) Hybrid inheritance",
            "(d) Hierarchical inheritance"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 452,
        "question": "A derived class with only one base class is called",
        "answer": "(c) Single inheritance",
        "options": [
            "(a) Multilevel inheritance",
            "(b) Multiple inheritance",
            "(c) Single inheritance",
            "(d) Hierarchical inheritance"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 453,
        "question": "The duplication of inherited members due to multiple paths can be avoided by making a common base class as a",
        "answer": "(b) Virtual base class",
        "options": [
            "(a) Abstract class",
            "(b) Virtual base class",
            "(c) Multiple inheritance",
            "(d) Nesting of classes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 454,
        "question": "The operators that can't be overloaded are",
        "answer": "(c) Ternary operator",
        "options": [
            "(a) Binary operators",
            "(b) Unary operators",
            "(c) Ternary operator",
            "(d) None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 455,
        "question": "A friend function for unary operator overloading takes ___ arguments.",
        "answer": "(a) Zero",
        "options": [
            "(a) Zero",
            "(b) One",
            "(c) Two",
            "(d) None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 456,
        "question": "A friend function for binary operator overloading takes ___ arguments.",
        "answer": "(c) Two",
        "options": [
            "(a) Zero",
            "(b) One",
            "(c) Two",
            "(d) None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 457,
        "question": "The variable that contains the address of a constant or variable is called a",
        "answer": "(c) Pointer",
        "options": [
            "(a) Function",
            "(b) Array",
            "(c) Pointer",
            "(d) Structure"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 458,
        "question": "The memory management operators in C++ are",
        "answer": "(a) New & delete",
        "options": [
            "(a) New & delete",
            "(b) Malloc",
            "(c) Calloc",
            "(d) Free"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 459,
        "question": "The pointer that refers to an object that has called the member function currently is",
        "answer": "(a) This",
        "options": [
            "(a) This",
            "(b) Address",
            "(c) Virtual function",
            "(d) None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 460,
        "question": "The empty virtual functions are called",
        "answer": "(a) Pure virtual functions",
        "options": [
            "(a) Pure virtual functions",
            "(b) Virtual table",
            "(c) Polymorphism",
            "(d) Virtual base class"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 461,
        "question": "A stream of bytes that is the interface between IO and IO devices is called a",
        "answer": "(d) File",
        "options": [
            "(a) Streams",
            "(b) Class",
            "(c) Object",
            "(d) File"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 462,
        "question": "The class derived from standard library ios that contains input functions is",
        "answer": "(b) Istream",
        "options": [
            "(a) ios",
            "(b) Istream",
            "(c) Stream",
            "(d) Ostream"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 463,
        "question": "The class derived from standard library ios that contains output functions is",
        "answer": "(d) Ostream",
        "options": [
            "(a) ios",
            "(b) Ostream",
            "(c) Stream",
            "(d) Ostream"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 464,
        "question": "When class B is inherited from class A, what is the order in which the constructors of those classes are called?",
        "answer": "(a) Class A first Class B next",
        "options": [
            "(a) Class A first Class B next",
            "(b) Class B first Class A next",
            "(c) Class B's only as it is the child class",
            "(d) Class A's only as it is the parent class"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 465,
        "question": "Which of the following is the most general exception handler that catches exceptions of 'any type'?",
        "answer": "(c) catch(...)",
        "options": [
            "(a) catch(std::exception)",
            "(b) catch(std::any_exception)",
            "(c) catch(...)",
            "(d) catch()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 466,
        "question": "In a group of nested loops, which loop is executed the most number of times?",
        "answer": "(b) the innermost loop",
        "options": [
            "(a) the outermost loop",
            "(b) the innermost loop",
            "(c) all loops are executed the same number of times",
            "(d) cannot be determined without knowing the size of the loops"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 467,
        "question": "Inline functions are invoked at the time of",
        "answer": "(b) Compile time",
        "options": [
            "(a) Run time",
            "(b) Compile time",
            "(c) Depends on how it is invoked",
            "(d) Both 2 and 3 above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 468,
        "question": "Statement scanf(\"%d\",80);",
        "answer": "(b) Give an error message",
        "options": [
            "(a) Assign an integer to variable i",
            "(b) Give an error message",
            "(c) Print the value of i",
            "(d) Assign a float to variable i"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 469,
        "question": "Which looping process is best used when the number of iterations is known?",
        "answer": "(a) for",
        "options": [
            "(a) for",
            "(b) while",
            "(c) do-while",
            "(d) all looping processes require that the iterations be known"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 470,
        "question": "In C, '3' represents",
        "answer": "(c) A character",
        "options": [
            "(a) A digit",
            "(b) An integer",
            "(c) A character",
            "(d) A word"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 471,
        "question": "The output of this program is Int a = 10; void main() { int a = 20; cout << a << a; }",
        "answer": "(d) 20 20",
        "options": [
            "(a) Syntax error",
            "(b) 10 20",
            "(c) 2010",
            "(d) 20 20"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 472,
        "question": "How many types of polymorphisms are supported by C++?",
        "answer": "(b) 2",
        "options": [
            "(a) 3",
            "(b) 2",
            "(c) 1",
            "(d) 4"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 473,
        "question": "Which of the following correctly describes overloading of functions?",
        "answer": "(a) Ad-hoc polymorphism",
        "options": [
            "(a) Ad-hoc polymorphism",
            "(b) Transient polymorphism",
            "(c) Virtual polymorphism",
            "(d) Pseudo polymorphism"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 474,
        "question": "Which of the following is also known as an instance of a class?",
        "answer": "(b) Object",
        "options": [
            "(a) Friend Functions",
            "(b) Object",
            "(c) Member Variables",
            "(d) Member Functions"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 475,
        "question": "Which of the following means \"The use of an object of one class in definition of another class\"?",
        "answer": "(c) Composition",
        "options": [
            "(a) Encapsulation",
            "(b) Abstraction",
            "(c) Composition",
            "(d) Inheritance"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 476,
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
        "answer": "(a) The default value for an argument cannot be a function call.",
        "options": [
            "(a) The default value for an argument cannot be a function call.",
            "(b) C++ does not allow the redefinition of a default parameter.",
            "(c) Both (a) and (b)",
            "(d) C++ allows the redefinition of a default parameter."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 477,
        "question": "Which of the following function/types of function cannot have default parameters?",
        "answer": "(c) main()",
        "options": [
            "(a) Member function of class",
            "(b) Member function of structure",
            "(c) main()",
            "(d) Both (b) and (c)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 478,
        "question": "What happens when a class with parameterized constructors and having no default constructor is used in a program and we create an object that needs a zero-argument constructor?",
        "answer": "(c) Compile-time error",
        "options": [
            "(a) Runtime error",
            "(b) Preprocessing error",
            "(c) Compile-time error",
            "(d) Runtime exception"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 479,
        "question": "Which of the following never requires any arguments?",
        "answer": "(a) Default constructor",
        "options": [
            "(a) Default constructor",
            "(b) Friend function",
            "(c) Member function",
            "(d) Const function"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 480,
        "question": "Which one of the following is a keyword?",
        "answer": "(d) Switch",
        "options": [
            "(a) Size",
            "(b) Key",
            "(c) Jump",
            "(d) Switch"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 481,
        "question": "___ is the smallest individual unit in a program.",
        "answer": "(d) Token",
        "options": [
            "(a) Variable",
            "(b) Control",
            "(c) Character",
            "(d) Token"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 482,
        "question": "Virtual functions can't be made friend functions of other classes.",
        "answer": "(a) True",
        "options": [
            "(a) True",
            "(b) False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 483,
        "question": "The modulus operator uses the ___ character.",
        "answer": "(d) %",
        "options": [
            "(a) +",
            "(b) -",
            "(c) /",
            "(d) %"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 484,
        "question": "Auto, static, extern, and register are called",
        "answer": "(d) Storage specifiers",
        "options": [
            "(a) Static",
            "(b) Register",
            "(c) Auto",
            "(d) Storage specifiers"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 485,
        "question": "Signed, unsigned, long, and short are some of the",
        "answer": "(d) Modifiers",
        "options": [
            "(a) Void",
            "(b) Data",
            "(c) Derived data",
            "(d) Modifiers"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 486,
        "question": "Float and double are related to the ___ data type.",
        "answer": "(b) Floating",
        "options": [
            "(a) Void",
            "(b) Floating",
            "(c) Fixed",
            "(d) Integral"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 487,
        "question": "Integer values are stored in ___ bit format in binary form.",
        "answer": "(c) 32",
        "options": [
            "(a) 8",
            "(b) 16",
            "(c) 32",
            "(d) 64"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 488,
        "question": "Addressing is done using the ___ number system.",
        "answer": "(b) Hexadecimal",
        "options": [
            "(a) Decimal",
            "(b) Hexadecimal",
            "(c) Octal",
            "(d) Binary"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 489,
        "question": "The ___ operator requires two operands.",
        "answer": "(b) Binary",
        "options": [
            "(a) Logical",
            "(b) Binary",
            "(c) Unary",
            "(d) Ternary"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 490,
        "question": "The keyword void is used to declare",
        "answer": "(d) Absence of a type",
        "options": [
            "(a) Objects that can be modified outside of program control",
            "(b) A synonym for an existing type",
            "(c) A member function that is defined in a subclass",
            "(d) Absence of a type"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 491,
        "question": "Run-time polymorphism in a C++ program is",
        "answer": "(d) None",
        "options": [
            "(a) New and delete operator overloading",
            "(b) ++ and -- operator overloading",
            "(c) operator overloading",
            "(d) None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 492,
        "question": "In function overloading, do not use the ___ function name for two unrelated functions.",
        "answer": "(a) Same",
        "options": [
            "(a) Same",
            "(b) Different",
            "(c) Similar",
            "(d) Complement"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 493,
        "question": "Which type of inheritance leads to the diamond problem?",
        "answer": "(c) Multiple",
        "options": [
            "(a) Single level",
            "(b) Multi-level",
            "(c) Multiple",
            "(d) Hierarchical"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 494,
        "question": "If a derived class object is created, which constructor is called first?",
        "answer": "(a) Base class constructor",
        "options": [
            "(a) Base class constructor",
            "(b) Derived class constructor",
            "(c) Depends on how we call the object",
            "(d) Not possible"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 495,
        "question": "When the inheritance is private, the private methods in base class in the derived class (in C++) are",
        "answer": "(a) Inaccessible",
        "options": [
            "(a) Inaccessible",
            "(b) Accessible",
            "(c) Protected",
            "(d) Public"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 496,
        "question": "What is meant by multiple inheritance?",
        "answer": "(c) Deriving a derived class from more than one base class",
        "options": [
            "(a) Deriving a base class from derived class",
            "(b) Deriving a derived class from base class",
            "(c) Deriving a derived class from more than one base class",
            "(d) None of the mentioned"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 497,
        "question": "Inheritance allows in C++ Program?",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Class Re-usability",
            "(b) Creating a hierarchy of classes",
            "(c) Extendibility",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 498,
        "question": "Which symbol is used to create multiple inheritances?",
        "answer": "(b) Comma",
        "options": [
            "(a) Dot",
            "(b) Comma",
            "(c) Dollar",
            "(d) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 499,
        "question": "Which of the following can be overloaded?",
        "answer": "(c) Both a & b",
        "options": [
            "(a) Object",
            "(b) Operators",
            "(c) Both a & b",
            "(d) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 500,
        "question": "Which stores a fixed-size sequential collection of elements of the same type?",
        "answer": "(b) Array",
        "options": [
            "(a) Loop",
            "(b) Array",
            "(c) Exception",
            "(d) Number"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 501,
        "question": "All arrays consist of",
        "answer": "(b) Contiguous memory locations",
        "options": [
            "(a) Simple",
            "(b) Contiguous memory locations",
            "(c) Distant",
            "(d) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 502,
        "question": "The lowest address of an array is?",
        "answer": "(a) 0",
        "options": [
            "(a) 0",
            "(b) 1",
            "(c) 2",
            "(d) 3"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 503,
        "question": "C++ supports multidimensional arrays?",
        "answer": "(a) Yes",
        "options": [
            "(a) Yes",
            "(b) No",
            "(c) Can be yes or no",
            "(d) Cannot say"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 504,
        "question": "What is the scope of the variable declared in the user-defined function?",
        "answer": "(b) Only inside the {} block",
        "options": [
            "(a) Whole program",
            "(b) Only inside the {} block",
            "(c) The main function",
            "(d) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 505,
        "question": "Which of the following in Object-Oriented Programming is supported by function overloading and default arguments features of C++?",
        "answer": "(b) Polymorphism",
        "options": [
            "(a) Inheritance",
            "(b) Polymorphism",
            "(c) Encapsulation",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 506,
        "question": "Logical AND (&&) and Logical OR (||) are _____ operators.",
        "answer": "(a) Logical",
        "options": [
            "(a) Logical",
            "(b) Equality",
            "(c) Class member",
            "(d) Comma"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 507,
        "question": "Generic pointers can be declared with",
        "answer": "(b) void",
        "options": [
            "(a) auto",
            "(b) void",
            "(c) asm",
            "(d) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 508,
        "question": "What is the size of a generic pointer in C?",
        "answer": "(c) 2",
        "options": [
            "(a) 0",
            "(b) 1",
            "(c) 2",
            "(d) Null"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 509,
        "question": "A void pointer cannot point to which of these?",
        "answer": "(c) Both a & b",
        "options": [
            "(a) Methods in C++",
            "(b) Class member in C++",
            "(c) Both a & b",
            "(d) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 510,
        "question": "Which stream class is used to only write on files?",
        "answer": "(a) ofstream",
        "options": [
            "(a) ofstream",
            "(b) ifstream",
            "(c) fstream",
            "(d) iostream"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 511,
        "question": "It is not possible to combine two or more file opening modes in open() method.",
        "answer": "(a) TRUE",
        "options": [
            "(a) TRUE",
            "(b) FALSE",
            "(c) May be",
            "(d) Can't say"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 512,
        "question": "If we have an object from the ofstream class, then the default mode of opening the file is",
        "answer": "(a) ios::out",
        "options": [
            "(a) ios::out",
            "(b) ios::in",
            "(c) ios::trunc",
            "(d) ios::out | ios::trunc"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 513,
        "question": "When fopen() is not able to open a file, it returns",
        "answer": "(b) null",
        "options": [
            "(a) eof",
            "(b) null",
            "(c) runtime error",
            "(d) compiler dependent"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 514,
        "question": "By default, all the files are opened in which of the following modes?",
        "answer": "(b) Text Mode",
        "options": [
            "(a) Binary Mode",
            "(b) Text Mode",
            "(c) Sequential Mode",
            "(d) Both 1 and 2"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 515,
        "question": "We can prevent a function from throwing any exceptions.",
        "answer": "(a) TRUE",
        "options": [
            "(a) TRUE",
            "(b) FALSE",
            "(c) May be",
            "(d) Can't say"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 516,
        "question": "Which type of program is recommended to include in a try block?",
        "answer": "(b) Dynamic memory allocation",
        "options": [
            "(a) Static memory allocation",
            "(b) Dynamic memory allocation",
            "(c) Const reference",
            "(d) Pointer"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 517,
        "question": "What does STL stand for?",
        "answer": "(b) Standard Template Library",
        "options": [
            "(a) Simple Template Library",
            "(b) Standard Template Library",
            "(c) Static Type Library",
            "(d) Single Type-based Library"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 518,
        "question": "Which one of the following is not a valid reserved keyword in C++?",
        "answer": "(c) implicit",
        "options": [
            "(a) Explicit",
            "(b) Public",
            "(c) implicit",
            "(d) Private"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 519,
        "question": "Each pass through a loop is called a/an",
        "answer": "(b) iteration",
        "options": [
            "(a) enumeration",
            "(b) iteration",
            "(c) culmination",
            "(d) pass through"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 520,
        "question": "Which of the following relationships is known as an inheritance relationship?",
        "answer": "(b) is-a relationship",
        "options": [
            "(a) has-a relationship",
            "(b) is-a relationship",
            "(c) association relationship",
            "(d) none of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 521,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a component of the file system?",
        "answer": "(d) None of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Access method",
            "(b) Auxiliary storage management",
            "(c) Free integrity mechanism",
            "(d) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 522,
        "question": "Which looping process checks the test condition at the end of the loop?",
        "answer": "(c) do-while",
        "options": [
            "(a) for",
            "(b) while",
            "(c) do-while",
            "(d) no looping process checks the test condition at the end"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 523,
        "question": "The default access level assigned to members of a class is",
        "answer": "(a) Private",
        "options": [
            "(a) Private",
            "(b) Public",
            "(c) Protected",
            "(d) Needs to be assigned"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 524,
        "question": "Which of the following languages is a subset of the C++ language?",
        "answer": "(a) C language",
        "options": [
            "(a) C language",
            "(b) Java Language",
            "(c) Python language",
            "(d) Ruby language"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 525,
        "question": "How do we declare an 'interface' class?",
        "answer": "(a) By making all the methods pure virtual in class",
        "options": [
            "(a) By making all the methods pure virtual in class",
            "(b) By making all the methods abstract using the keyword 'abstract' in a class",
            "(c) By declaring the class as interface with keyword 'interface'",
            "(d) It is not possible to create an interface class in C++"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 526,
        "question": "What happens when a pointer is deleted twice?",
        "answer": "(c) It can cause an error",
        "options": [
            "(a) It can abort the program",
            "(b) It can cause a failure",
            "(c) It can cause an error",
            "(d) It can cause a trap"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 527,
        "question": "Which of the following language features is not an access specifier in C++?",
        "answer": "(d) internal",
        "options": [
            "(a) public",
            "(b) private",
            "(c) protected",
            "(d) internal"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 528,
        "question": "The statement i++; is equivalent to",
        "answer": "(b) i=i+1;",
        "options": [
            "(a) i=i+i;",
            "(b) i=i+1;",
            "(c) i=1-1;",
            "(d) i--;"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 529,
        "question": "Which of the following library functions by default aborts the program?",
        "answer": "(c) Abort()",
        "options": [
            "(a) Terminate()",
            "(b) end()",
            "(c) Abort()",
            "(d) exit()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 530,
        "question": "Vtables",
        "answer": "(c) creates a dynamic table per class",
        "options": [
            "(a) creates a static table per class",
            "(b) creates a static table per object",
            "(c) creates a dynamic table per class",
            "(d) creates a dynamic table per object"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 531,
        "question": "How structures and classes in C++ differ?",
        "answer": "(b) In Structures, members are public by default whereas, Classes, they are private by default",
        "options": [
            "(a) Structures by default hide every member whereas classes not",
            "(b) In Structures, members are public by default whereas, Classes, they are private by default",
            "(c) Structures cannot have private members whereas classes have",
            "(d) In Structures, members are private by default whereas, Classes, they are public by default"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 532,
        "question": "What is the benefit of C++ input and output over C input and output?",
        "answer": "(a) Both Type safety & Exception",
        "options": [
            "(a) Both Type safety & Exception",
            "(b) Sequence container",
            "(c) Exception",
            "(d) Type safety"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 533,
        "question": "What will be the output of the following C++ program?\n\n#include <iostream>\n#include <string>\n\nusing namespace std;\n\nint main() {\n    string str(\"Sanfoundry\");\n    for(size_t i = 0; i < str.length(); i++)\n        cout << str.at(i);\n    return 0;\n}",
        "answer": "(d) Sanfoundry",
        "options": [
            "(a) runtime error",
            "(b) runtime",
            "(c) S",
            "(d) Sanfoundry"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 534,
        "question": "Which of the following is 'address of' operator?",
        "answer": "(b) &",
        "options": [
            "(a) *",
            "(b) &",
            "(c) * (d) &&"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 535,
        "question": "goto can be classified into?",
        "answer": "(a) label",
        "options": [
            "(a) label",
            "(b) variable",
            "(c) operator",
            "(d) function"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 536,
        "question": "Identify the correct definition of operator in pointer?",
        "answer": "(a) Address of operator",
        "options": [
            "(a) Address of operator",
            "(b) Value of address operator",
            "(c) Manipulation operator",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 537,
        "question": "By which of the following can the if-else statement be replaced?",
        "answer": "(c) Conditional operator",
        "options": [
            "(a) Bitwise operator",
            "(b) Logical operator",
            "(c) Conditional operator",
            "(d) Arithmetic operator"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 538,
        "question": "Using which of the following data types can 19.54 be represented?",
        "answer": "(b) double",
        "options": [
            "(a) void",
            "(b) double",
            "(c) int",
            "(d) None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 539,
        "question": "Choose the correct option which is mandatory in a function?",
        "answer": "(d) Both 1 and 3",
        "options": [
            "(a) Return type",
            "(b) Parameters",
            "(c) Function name",
            "(d) Both 1 and 3"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 540,
        "question": "The constants in C++ are also known as?",
        "answer": "(b) Literals",
        "options": [
            "(a) Pre-processor",
            "(b) Literals",
            "(c) Const",
            "(d) None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 541,
        "question": "Identify the size of int datatype in C++?",
        "answer": "(d) Depends on compiler",
        "options": [
            "(a) 1 byte",
            "(b) 2 bytes",
            "(c) 4 bytes",
            "(d) Depends on compiler"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 542,
        "question": "What is the ASCII value of '10' character?",
        "answer": "(d) 0",
        "options": [
            "(a) 32",
            "(b) 24",
            "(c) 48",
            "(d) 0"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 543,
        "question": "Identify the format string among the following?",
        "answer": "(c) %d",
        "options": [
            "(a) &",
            "(b) in",
            "(c) %d",
            "(d) None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 544,
        "question": "Choose the type of loop which is guaranteed to execute at least once?",
        "answer": "(b) do-while",
        "options": [
            "(a) for loop",
            "(b) do-while",
            "(c) while",
            "(d) None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 545,
        "question": "What does a C++ class hold?",
        "answer": "(d) Both a and b",
        "options": [
            "(a) Function",
            "(b) Data",
            "(c) Arrays",
            "(d) Both a and b"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 546,
        "question": "Under which pillar of OOPS does base class and derived class relationship come?",
        "answer": "(b) Inheritance",
        "options": [
            "(a) Polymorphism",
            "(b) Inheritance",
            "(c) Encapsulation",
            "(d) Abstraction"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 547,
        "question": "Which of the following functions can be inherited from a base class?",
        "answer": "(d) None",
        "options": [
            "(a) Constructor",
            "(b) Destructor",
            "(c) Static",
            "(d) None"
        ]
    },
]    